<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
<channel><title>The Register</title>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 23:20:18 -0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title> AWS Middle East disrupted after ‘objects struck datacenter’ amid Iran war </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/03/01/asia_tech_news_roundup/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 23:04:50 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   One of Amazon Web Services’ availability zones in the United Arab Emirates is offline after the facility was hit by unknown objects.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Amazon’s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://health.aws.amazon.com/health/status&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    status page
   &lt;/a&gt;
   indicated a “localized power issue has affected a single Availability Zone in the ME-CENTRAL-1 Region (mec1-az2)” as of 5:19 AM PST on March 1st.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   At 9:41 AM the same day AWS said the availability zone “was impacted by objects that struck the datacenter, creating sparks and fire. The fire department shut off power to the facility and generators as they worked to put out the fire.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   AWS has not explained what the objects were or where they came from, but a likely explanation is debris from the conflict between the USA and Israel, and Iran as numerous
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/live/cn5ge95q6y7t&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    reports
   &lt;/a&gt;
   confirm explosions in the Emirates after the conflict commenced.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The cloudy concern has advised users they may experience errors when calling EC2 APIs.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   At 2:28 PM PST AWS said it was &quot;seeing positive signs of recovery for many of the EC2 APIs&quot; and advised it would resolve them in two to three hours.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Australia’s WiseTech uses AI to halve headcount
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Australian supply chain software vendor WiseTech Global last week announced it will reduce headcount by half – meaning up to 2,000 job cuts – due to increased adoption of AI.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “The era of manually writing code as the core act of engineering is over,” wrote CEO Zubin Appoo in a
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn-api.markitdigital.com/apiman-gateway/ASX/asx-research/1.0/file/2924-03060852-2A1655794&amp;v=undefined&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    regulatory filing
   &lt;/a&gt;
   . [PDF] “AI amplifies the productivity of our expertise in logistics … and it allows us to move faster from ideas to real customer value from efficiencies it brings in software development and product creation.” Appoo said the job cuts will first be felt in product &amp; development teams, and in customer service roles.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Samsung plans autonomous factories
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Samsung Electronics on Sunday
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-electronics-announces-strategy-to-transition-global-manufacturing-into-ai-driven-factories-by-2030&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    announced
   &lt;/a&gt;
   its intention to operate autonomous factories by 2030.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “This initiative aims to fully integrate AI across the entire manufacturing value chain — from inbound material logistics and production to quality inspection and final shipment — establishing a next-generation autonomous production environment,” according to a company statement that envisions “specialized AI agents dedicated to quality control, production and logistics.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The statement says Samsung will use this tech “across its global manufacturing network.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The company has framed this move as a “transition from automation to advanced autonomy” and says it will involve “progressively introducing humanoid and task-specialized robotics across its production lines, including Operating Robots for line operations and facility management, Logistics Robots for autonomous material handling and transport and Assembly Robots for precision manufacturing tasks.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/asia_tech_news_roundup/&quot;&gt;
     Infosys chair says AI will clean up legacy systems – then make more of them
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/16/asia_tech_news_roundup/&quot;&gt;
     US appears open to reversing some China tech bans
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/09/asia_tech_news_roundup/&quot;&gt;
     Indian police commissioner wants ID cards for AI agents
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/02/asia_tech_news_roundup/&quot;&gt;
     India dangles 20-year tax holiday for clouds that serve offshore users
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Micron opens Indian plant
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Memory-maker Micron Technology last week
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.micron.com/news-releases/news-release-details/micron-celebrates-opening-indias-first-semiconductor-assembly&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    opened
   &lt;/a&gt;
   its first plant in India, a semiconductor assembly and test facility in Sanand, Gujarat, that it will use to convert DRAM and NAND wafers from into finished memory and storage products.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Micron
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/06/23/micron_india_assembly_facility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    announced
   &lt;/a&gt;
   the plant in 2023. Last Friday’s announcement admits that the facility is not yet completed, but stated “Once fully ramped, the first phase of Micron’s Sanand operation will feature more than 500,000 square feet of cleanroom space, making it one of the world’s largest single-floor assembly and test cleanrooms.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Indonesia signs Arm training deal
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The government of Indonesia last week
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://setkab.go.id/en/president-prabowo-witnesses-danantara-arm-partnership-to-accelerate-semiconductor-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    signed
   &lt;/a&gt;
   a strategic partnership with UK chip design house Arm that will see the nation try to train 15,000 engineers on the company’s ecosystem.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Minister of Investment and Downstream Industries Rosan Perkasa Roeslani, who is also CEO of Indonesia’s sovereign wealth fund Danantara, said some Indonesian engineers will be sent abroad for training, and others will participate in sessions run by Arm trainers who visit the nation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rosan said the scheme will see Indonesia’s government select six industries to acquire chip development expertise, as the nation seeks to tap the global semiconductor boom.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Uber Dubai adds flying taxis
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Uber last week
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2026/Get-Ready-for-Takeoff-With-Uber-and-Joby/default.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    announced
   &lt;/a&gt;
   it will add the option to hail a flying taxi to its app in the United Arab Emirates.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Uber&#x27;s visualization of its app and a Joby flying taxi&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/03/01/supplied_uber_dubai_joby.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Uber&#x27;s visualization of its app and a Joby flying taxi&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   US-based Joby will provide the flying cabs, which Uber says will carry paying passengers “later this year.” ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Lenovo shows off snap-together laptop with removable keyboard, screen, and ports </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/03/01/lenovo_shows_off_modular_laptop/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 23:04:44 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   If you own a desktop computer, you&#x27;re used to swapping parts and peripherals around, but most laptops are closed boxes with few ways to modify them. Lenovo&#x27;s new ThinkBook Modular AI PC concept shows what happens when you can remove a screen, a keyboard, and even blocks of ports from a mobile PC.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The computer maker is showing off the concept at Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. We had a chance to see the ThinkBook concept at a Lenovo press event in early February and came away impressed with the company&#x27;s ambitious attempt to improve productivity by letting you move some components around. The system comes standard with a 14-inch, 4K 120 Hz OLED touch panel you can&#x27;t pull off, but there&#x27;s a secondary display you can attach to the back of the lid via a magnetic connection, or use as a standalone second monitor by connecting with a wire, or snap onto the deck, giving you a dual-screen laptop like the Yoga Book 9i.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo7.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo ThinkBook Modular AI PC Concept&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo7.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo ThinkBook Modular AI PC Concept&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo ThinkBook Modular AI PC Concept - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The laptop has two of Lenovo&#x27;s Magic Bay magnetic 11 pogo pin connectors, one on the back of the lid and one beneath the keyboard. These connectors, which have appeared on shipping ThinkBooks such as the ThinkBook 16p Gen 4 before, allow you to connect a light, a webcam, or a 4G modem. Now, they&#x27;re being used to connect the second screen and the keyboard.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo4.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo&#x27;s screen attaches to the Magic Bay&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo4.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo&#x27;s screen attaches to the Magic Bay&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo&#x27;s screen attaches to the Magic Bay - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The keyboard itself pops off, so you can use that space for attaching the second panel. Even if the keyboard is not physically connected to the ThinkBook, you can still use it via Bluetooth, allowing you to have both a dual-screen laptop and a keyboard at the same time.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Beneath the keyboard perch two removable port blocks you can use to swap out ports. On the right side, you can remove the HDMI port and, on the left, there&#x27;s a pop-off USB-C port. Though the company did not show this during its demo, we assume that Lenovo would offer alternate port blocks you could pop on in their place if this laptop ever came to market.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo5.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;The ThinkBook Modular also has removable ports.&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo5.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;The ThinkBook Modular also has removable ports.&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    The ThinkBook Modular also has removable ports. - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   If you want to use the second screen like an external monitor, there&#x27;s a magnetic stand that snaps onto the back of it and allows you to swap between portrait and landscape modes. When not in use, this stand serves as a foot for the laptop, snapping onto the bottom surface.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo9.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;The ThinkBook&#x27;s monitor stand attaches to the bottom like a foot&quot; height=&quot;324&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo9.jpg?x=648&amp;y=324&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;The ThinkBook&#x27;s monitor stand attaches to the bottom like a foot&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    The ThinkBook&#x27;s monitor stand attaches to the bottom like a foot - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   On the inside, the ThinkBook Modular AI PC concept is very much like other 14-inch business laptops. It sports an Intel Core Ultra 7 255H &quot;Arrow Lake&quot; processor, which is not the very latest generation of Intel processor (that would be &quot;Panther Lake&quot;). But since this is a concept PC, we can assume that if it were to come out, it would probably have whatever CPU is current as of that time.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It has a generous 32 GB of RAM, a 1 TB PCIe SSD, an 8 MP camera and a 33 Wh battery. The laptop measures a reasonable 12.3 x 9.2 inches, but with a chunky 0.94 inch thickness. It weighs a very light 2.5 pounds with just one display, but that number jumps up to a still-reasonable 3.1 pounds with the second screen attached. Like other ThinkBooks, it&#x27;s a dull and corporate-friendly shade of gray – in this case, Luna Gray.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Since this is a concept laptop, we have no idea what such a device would cost, although it won&#x27;t be cheap – especially if this year&#x27;s memory crunch
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/memory_price_hikes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    still continues
   &lt;/a&gt;
   . By way of comparison, last year&#x27;s ThinkBook with rolling screen was $3,500. But even if this exact configuration never sees the light of day, we wouldn&#x27;t be surprised to see Lenovo use this modularity idea in a future ThinkBook.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   New ThinkPads come in blue, are more fixable than ever
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Lenovo&#x27;s mainstream T-series ThinkPads are getting a major refresh for 2026 as new models of the T14 (Gen 7), T14s (Gen 7), and T16 (Gen 5) are all due out this spring. For the first time, the 14-inch models will be available in Cosmic Blue, a new dark blue colorway that has never been used on ThinkPads before. You&#x27;ll still be able to get classic black, of course.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   I got a chance to see some Cosmic Blue ThinkPads in person and I found the shade to be very dark and subtle. Only in very direct lighting could I even tell that they were blue, not black.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo6a.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad T14 in Cosmic Blue&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo6a.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad T14 in Cosmic Blue&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo ThinkPad T14 in Cosmic Blue - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   On the inside, the ThinkPads will be powered by your choice of CPU platform. The ThinkPad T14s will be available with the most options: an Intel Core Ultra Series 3 chip, AMD Ryzen AI PRO 400 inside, or Qualcomm Snapdragon X2 SoC that uses Windows on Arm. The ThinkPad T14 and T16 will come in either Intel (Ultra Series 3) or AMD Ryzen AI.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   As always, the ThinkPad T14s (the &quot;s&quot; is for slim) is the sleekest of the bunch, tipping the scales at 2.45 to 2.66 pounds while being only 0.7 inches thick. The ThinkPad T14, which also has a 14-inch display, is a few tenths of a pound heavier and about 0.1 inch thicker. The 16-inch ThinkPad T16 is obviously the heaviest of the bunch at 3.62 pounds and it&#x27;s almost an inch thick.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/thinkpad-t14s.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad T14s&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/thinkpad-t14s.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad T14s&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo ThinkPad T14s - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The two thicker ThinkPads are easier to repair than ever, earning iFixit repairability scores of 10 out of 10. As I watched, Lenovo reps showed me how easy it is to remove the back plate, the battery, the SSD, the keyboard, and even the USB-C ports for replacement. This is a huge step up from prior models, where you had to remove large components to get to some of these parts.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;ThinkPad T14 Gen 7 is easy to repair&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo1.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;ThinkPad T14 Gen 7 is easy to repair&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    ThinkPad T14 Gen 7 is easy to repair - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Intel-powered models of the T14 and T16 use LPCAMM2 RAM, which is screwed onto the motherboard and can be easily replaced. So, if you buy one of these laptops with only 16 GB of RAM and you later want to upgrade to 32 or 64 GB, that will be possible, though with the price of memory these days, it may not be desirable.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   All three laptops will be available in Q2, with the ThinkPad T14s starting at $1,899, while the T14 and T16 both start at $1,799.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   New detachable challenges the Surface in business environments
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   If you&#x27;re looking for a laptop where the screen comes off of the keyboard, Lenovo has a new option in the ThinkPad X13 detachable. This 13-inch system looks and feels like the ThinkPad version of the Microsoft Surface Pro with a keyboard that magnetically attaches to the display.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo6.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad X13 Detachable&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo6.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo ThinkPad X13 Detachable&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo ThinkPad X13 Detachable - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   However, the keyboard promises to be better than what you&#x27;d find on a Surface tablet because it uses Lenovo&#x27;s famous ThinkPad keyboard tech, which has a unique combination of tactile feedback, smile-shaped keys, and generous travel. In fact, the company boasts that the X13 Detachable&#x27;s keys have a full 1.5 mm of travel, the same amount as a ThinkPad X1 Carbon.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In addition to the keyboard, there&#x27;s a Lenovo Slim Pen that charges in the keyboard.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/07/lenovo_rollable_thinkpad/&quot;&gt;
     Lenovo shows off new laptops that twist and roll
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/02/thinkpad_david_hill_interview/&quot;&gt;
     Long live the nub: ThinkPad designer David Hill spills secrets, designs that never made it
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/17/ai_arm_and_copilot_living/&quot;&gt;
     Microsoft Surface 7 laptop: Nice hardware, shame about the OS
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/16/refurbished_pcs_memory_crunch/&quot;&gt;
     Secondhand laptop market goes &#x27;mainstream&#x27; amid memory crunch
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   On the inside, this is a full-powered PC, complete with an Intel Core Ultra Series 3 (Panther Lake) processor, up to 64 GB of LPDDR5x RAM, and up to 2 TB of SSD storage. Its 13-inch display operates at a 2880 x 1920 resolution and promises to reproduce up to 100 percent of the sRGB color gamut.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The ThinkPad X13 detachable will be available in Q3 for a starting price of $1,999.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Lenovo AI Workmate Concept is ready to help you project
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Lenovo also showed off a robot that reminds me a lot of the jumping Pixar lamp. This dark gray automaton sits on top of a table where it can rotate and bend its screen (aka face) to interact with you or help you.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo-workmate-concept.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Lenovo Workmate AI robot Concept&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/27/lenovo-workmate-concept.jpg?x=648&amp;y=364&amp;infer_y=1&quot; title=&quot;Lenovo Workmate AI robot Concept&quot; width=&quot;648&quot;/&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    Lenovo Workmate AI robot concept - Click to enlarge
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The AI-powered robot does local AI processing, where it can help you with presentations, note-taking, and meeting summarization. It also has a projector on it, so it can output your slides to everyone in the room.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This device was not working during our demo, so we didn&#x27;t get to see everything that it can do. It too is just a concept and, based on our experience, it&#x27;s not as likely to see the light of day as the ThinkBook Modular. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Harvard boffins finally crack the mystery of squeaky sneakers </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/harvard_boffins_squeaky_sneakers/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:22:40 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It is a sound evocative of high school: the characteristic squeak of sneakers on a basketball court. UK readers may, however, be familiar with the same sound from their trainers while playing badminton.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Whichever it is, how exactly the sound is produced has been a mystery - until now.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The high-pitched tones have often been attributed to the “stick-slip phenomenon,” which creates the sound from a violin bow moving against the instrument’s string. You can still read the explanation on the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stick%E2%80%93slip_phenomenon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Wikipedia page
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   But the problem is that the sound tends to show up at high sliding speeds, while it also has a well-defined pitch, the frequency of which is difficult to explain.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A team led by Harvard University postdoctoral researcher Adel Djellouli carried out an experimental analysis of the phenomenon and came up with an alternative to the stick-slip explanation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   They replicated the sneaker-court interface by testing rubber blocks sliding against a special glass plate. Light shone into the glass at an angle and was trapped inside — a phenomenon known as total internal reflection — and only released when the rubber made contact with the plate. The researchers were able to record the contact regions using a high-speed camera.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The results showed that the squeaking sound is produced by wave-like patterns across the rubber surface, contacting and then releasing from the glass, allowing the sliding between the surfaces. The waves move across the interface between the two materials at a speed of nearly 300 kilometers per hour.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/nasa_safety_artemis/&quot;&gt;
     NASA safety watchdog says it&#x27;s time to rethink Moon landing
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/moon_magnetic_field/&quot;&gt;
     Moon&#x27;s mighty magnetic field was a 5,000-year titanium blip
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/hubble_orbit_decay/&quot;&gt;
     Hubble in a death spiral that could end as early as 2028 without a reboost
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/pop_album_fatal_car_accidents/&quot;&gt;
     Pop music fans literally dying to stream hot new albums – in car crashes, that is
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Harvard team also found that including ridges in the rubber akin to the sole of a sneaker produced a dramatic effect. “In flat samples, these pulses are irregular and generate broadband acoustic emissions. Introducing thin surface ridges confines pulse propagation, yielding a consistent repetition frequency matching the first shear mode of the sliding block and squeaking at that frequency,” the paper,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-026-10132-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    published in Nature this week
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In an accompanying article, Bart Weber from the University of Amsterdam wrote that “The study not only explains a familiar sound but also reveals how much complexity can hide in the seemingly simple act of sliding.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The researchers also observed tiny triboelectric discharges, brief flashes of light that appear capable of triggering the surface waves.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Aside from explaining a curious effect from high school days, the researchers point to further work that could help enhance or reduce the effect, Weber said. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Denizens of DEF CON are &#x27;fed up with government&#x27; </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/28/def_con_jake_braun_fed_up_govt/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:32:16 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Hackers – especially Jake Braun – are &quot;fed up with government.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Braun was one of the creators of the first-ever
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2018/08/13/DEF%20CON_election_vote_hacking/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Voting Machine Hacking Village at DEF CON
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in 2017 and served as a homeland security and cyber advisor to the Obama and Biden administrations. He also co-founded the Franklin project, named for Benjamin Franklin, who founded America&#x27;s first volunteer fire department and published the annual Poor Richard&#x27;s Almanack – an eclectic collection of useful facts and other musings.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Franklin project, which
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/12/def_con_franklin_project_hopes_hackers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    launched at DEF CON
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in 2024, enlists hackers to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/10/def_con_hackers_water_security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    secure critical infrastructure
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and 350 people signed up that year to donate their time and talent to securing water facilities.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Another of the project’s activities is publishing an annual Hacker&#x27;s Almanack in homage to Franklin’s effort.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The second volume, the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://harris.uchicago.edu/sites/default/files/the_def_con_33_hackers_Almanack.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    DEF CON 33 Hackers&#x27; Almanack
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , [PDF] landed earlier this month.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
    We saw society moving in the right direction for the last 500 years because of our commitment to science, human rights, and that seems to be at the very least slowing down, if not reversing
   &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Thinking back to Ben Franklin, we saw society moving in the right direction for the last 500 years because of our commitment to science, human rights, etc., and that seems to be at the very least slowing down, if not reversing,” Braun told
   &lt;i&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/i&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Braun said he blames government for this state of affairs – pointedly &quot;the inability of government to continue to make the progress we saw from the enlightenment.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;This community is so committed to these principles of human rights and freedom of speech and science, that that when we see people fuck with them – or when we see the people that we elect to preserve these things not doing their fucking job – we&#x27;re just like: ‘Fuck you guys,’&quot; Braun said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Almanack highlights three major, all-of-society threats that governments have yet to fix: Cybercrime, AI, and - the biggie - authoritarianism. It presents a year&#x27;s worth of DEF CON research on these three topics and shows how hackers are responding to each one.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   AI for offense
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Braun says he and the rest of the DEF CON volunteers listened to &quot;dozens and dozens&quot; of talks before this year&#x27;s three topics bubbled to the surface.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We started seeing lots of
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/11/ai_security_offense_defense/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    instances where AI was winning
   &lt;/a&gt;
   or placing high in these hacker competitions, and that wasn&#x27;t happening last year,&quot; Braun said. &quot;That&#x27;s new and also something we&#x27;re worried about: When is this going to be the case that AI is as good as humans at hacking, and way better than humans [alone] once paired with a human?&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Anthropic researcher Keane Lucas entered his company&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/claude_code_security_panic/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    AI coding tool Claude
   &lt;/a&gt;
   into seven competitions during DEF CON 33, including capture-the-flag contests. During one of these - PicoCTF - it placed in the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbkeEwhWIks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    top three percent globally
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , while also successfully fending off red-team attacks in the Collegiate Cyber Defense Challenge.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Claude did struggle with more difficult challenges, and also made up some of its own flags.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Still, Claude&#x27;s performance and other research presented at the convention illustrate &quot;the accelerating power of AI for offense,&quot; according to the Almanack. Meanwhile, security remains an afterthought.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;There&#x27;s clearly more of a sense across the board than there was last year that we need the 20 critical controls for AI,&quot; Braun said, pointing to the Center for Internet Security&#x27;s (CIS)
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisecurity.org/controls/v8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Critical Security Controls
   &lt;/a&gt;
   as an example of what this would look like. &quot;We need an industry-wide, accepted definition like what CIS has been doing, and I don&#x27;t see any real movement toward that yet.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Combatting cybercrime
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This year&#x27;s cybercrime theme, &quot;Hackers don cape and mask,&quot; emerged after listening to accounts of DEF CON researchers performing feats such as taking down Russian dark web marketplace Solaris and its affiliated hacker collective, Killnet, and unveiling the real-world identity of phishing scammer Darcula, who is responsible for hundreds of thousands of people losing millions of dollars.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;These guys are taking down ransomware groups, and dealing with criminals in prison, and hacking the Russian firewall - it&#x27;s just fascinating,&quot; Braun said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Global governments&#x27; effort to fight ransomware and other types of cybercrime isn&#x27;t working, according to the Almanack. &quot;To properly fight back, policymakers need to unleash the full potential of programs like the FBIs Confidential Human Source (CHS) program, so we can leverage skilled white hat hackers as force multipliers to woefully outnumbered government authorities,&quot; it reads.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Down with despots
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The third theme, &quot;down with despots,&quot; didn&#x27;t come together until the end of the Almanack-writing process, as Braun saw examples of civil society methods to protect data, communications, and culture against censorship, surveilliance, and other kinds of oppression.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This included hacker LambdaCalculus&#x27;s off-grid mesh network,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://schedule.hope.net/hope16/speaker/XXHPGL/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    PirateBox
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , along with Jason Vogt and Josh Reiter&#x27;s proposal of setting up mesh networks in Taiwan to help civilians fight a future Chinese invasion.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Another talk by Saving Ukrainian Cultural Heritage Online (SUCHO) co-founder Quinn Dombrowski detailed his group&#x27;s effort to save Ukrainian cultural websites – libraries, archives, museums, and community organizations – before Russia’s invasion. It ultimately helped preserve more than 1,500 websites.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;This is all about preserving freedom and democracy from authoritarians that are oppressing the vulnerable populations around the world, whether they be Ukrainians, potentially the Taiwanes,e Uyghurs, or migrants for that matter,&quot; Braun said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/10/def_con_hackers_water_security/&quot;&gt;
     DEF CON hackers plug security holes in US water systems amid tsunami of threats
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/12/def_con_franklin_project_hopes_hackers/&quot;&gt;
     DEF CON Franklin project enlists hackers to harden critical infrastructure
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2018/08/13/DEF%20CON_election_vote_hacking/&quot;&gt;
     US voting systems: Full of holes, loaded with pop music, and &#x27;hacked&#x27; by an 11-year-old
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/11/ai_security_offense_defense/&quot;&gt;
     Red teams are safe from robots for now, as AI makes better shield than spear
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   To combat authoritarianism, the Almanack proposes building a Digital Arsenal of Democracy, comprised of technologies like mesh networks, digital archives, PirateBox, and DNA data storage to help oppressed communities to preserve their history and culture. Communication capabilities are also on the to-do list for the Arsenal’s creators.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This aligns with last year&#x27;s DEF CON theme – access everywhere – and, as Moses writes in an epilogue to the Almanack, will carry over to this summer&#x27;s focus on agency: &quot;The ability of a citizen to have agency over their identity, data, and persona.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   As Braun explains, &quot;It needs to be a concerted effort by the human rights community and the hacker community to sit down and look at what technologies are out there today that support the preservation of human rights around the world, figuring out what we don&#x27;t have, and then building those missing pieces,&quot; he said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Braun is confident that DEF CON hackers will rise to the challenge.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;There&#x27;s a certain thing in the hacker mindset that makes them a hacker: this commitment to freedom, transparency, science, very much Ben Franklin-esque,&quot; he said. &quot;When there&#x27;s threats to that, they get super riled up. I feel like we&#x27;re going to see a lot more research in this space because of what&#x27;s happening around the world, including here at home.&quot; ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> OpenClaw, but in containers: Meet NanoClaw </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/03/01/nanoclaw_container_openclaw/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:32:14 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ideally, you shouldn&#x27;t have to defend yourself against your own AI agent. But we don&#x27;t live in an ideal world and an unrestrained agent can cause a ton of damage.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   OpenClaw, an open source agent platform, made that obvious as its popularity surged over the past month and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/03/openclaw_security_problems/&quot;&gt;
    security incidents
   &lt;/a&gt;
   followed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Consider the case of Summer Yue, director of alignment at Meta Superintelligence Labs, who
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/summeryue0/status/2025774069124399363?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    posted last week
   &lt;/a&gt;
   about OpenClaw running amok and deleting her inbox. It&#x27;s clear that AI agents cannot be trusted.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Gavriel Cohen, a software engineer based in Israel, hopes to change that with a more secure, more constrained agent platform called
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanoclaw.net&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    NanoClaw
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   He
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/qwibitai/nanoclaw/commit/c17823a73231fa883c5861c3966c8b200197c5b7&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    started coding it
   &lt;/a&gt;
   at the end of January with the help of Anthropic&#x27;s Claude Code. And a few weeks later, Andrej Karpathy, an influential AI researcher, took notice amid his musing about how OpenClaw and other &quot;claws&quot; have become the orchestration layer for agents – LLMs given access to other software tools for task automation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;... NanoClaw looks really interesting in that the core engine is ~4000 lines of code (fits into both my head and that of AI agents, so it feels manageable, auditable, flexible, etc.) and runs everything in containers by default,&quot; Karpathy wrote in
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/karpathy/status/2024987174077432126?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    a social media post
   &lt;/a&gt;
   about a week ago. &quot;I also love their approach to configurability – it&#x27;s not done via config files, it&#x27;s done via skills!&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Cohen in an interview with
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   said that NanoClaw&#x27;s use of containers and its small codebase are what set the project apart from OpenClaw.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;They&#x27;re running bare metal with some application level checks to try to prevent it from accessing things it shouldn&#x27;t access,&quot; he explained. &quot;NanoClaw, each agent runs in its own container. And that&#x27;s really important. If you take the whole instance of OpenClaw and put it in a container, that doesn&#x27;t really help you because you&#x27;ve connected it to so many different things that are all in that container with the agent.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;With NanoClaw, the agent is running in a container where inside that container it&#x27;s just the agentic loop. It&#x27;s just the [Anthropic] Agent SDK. And if you&#x27;re connecting it to your WhatsApp, that agent doesn&#x27;t see all of your WhatsApp data. It only has the group that that specific agent has been connected to and the messages from the group that it should be seeing.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   With regard to the difference in codebase size between OpenClaw and NanoClaw, Cohen said that it&#x27;s unlikely that anyone has reviewed the 400,000 lines of code in OpenClaw, which undermines one of the assumptions about open source – that the community will catch and fix bugs.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   NanoClaw, he said, consists of a few thousand lines of code.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Anybody could review it, understand it, ask Claude a few questions if you need and get the sense of what&#x27;s the security model, what&#x27;s the architecture, how does it work, what are the sensitive points that I need to be careful when I&#x27;m touching,&quot; he said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Cohen said security concerns about OpenClaw led him to look for a better approach. A few months ago, he explained, he and his brother Lazer were building an AI-focused digital marketing agency. He&#x27;d set up a way for other people on the marketing team to access sales pipeline data from WhatsApp using Clawdbot (before the name became OpenClaw) to surface Obsidian vault data and Kanban scheduling details.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;In the beginning, it was OpenClaw as our chief of staff of sales,&quot; Cohen explained. &quot;It manages the sales pipeline. So we give it updates and it gives us tasks and we ask it to remind us and it reminds us. And it asks for status updates on deals.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Cohen said the agent went from asking questions to doing work and really filling the role of a sales chief.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The issue was, as soon as I set it up, I started to see massive security issues with OpenClaw,&quot; he explained. &quot;I mean I just saw issue after issue after issue and we were getting a ton of value from it, but it&#x27;s burning a hole in my subconscious, in the back of my head, knowing I have it running on my machine.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   He had OpenClaw running on a separate Mac mini but using a browser that was signed into his Chrome profile, and logged into his social media account.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;It&#x27;s a dedicated machine, but it was like literally keeping me up at night,&quot; he said. &quot;But at the same time, I have this conflict because I&#x27;m like, I wanna set up eight more of these agents to do other things with other jobs and other titles.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   About three weeks ago, when the OpenClaw machine network known as Moltbook began attracting broad attention, he said he realized he didn&#x27;t need the entire OpenClaw setup.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;All I need is agents that run in containers with isolation so that all the different groups with their different agents aren&#x27;t all in the same environment,&quot; he said. &quot;So I can give it full bash access, and it can install tools and run them and let it go wild, but only within the container and each one only accessing the data I wanted it to access.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;And I don&#x27;t need three thousand integrations. I only need like three things.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/amazon_nvidia_softbank_openai_megadeal/&quot;&gt;
     Amazon and Nvidia open their wallets to lock in OpenAI&#x27;s business while SoftBank keeps the lights on
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/anthropic_pentagon_response/&quot;&gt;
     Anthropic to Pentagon: Autonomous weapons could hurt US troops and civilians
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/block_q4_2025_ai_layoffs/&quot;&gt;
     Jack Dorsey&#x27;s fintech outfit Block announces 40% layoffs, blames AI, gets 23% stock bump
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/ai_models_get_better_at/&quot;&gt;
     AI models suck slightly less at math than they did last year
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rather than building NanoClaw on the Pi coding agent that&#x27;s the basis for OpenClaw, he chose to build around Claude Code because that&#x27;s his preferred AI coding tool.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;So I sat down and I built it and it took me a weekend to build what&#x27;s needed around Claude Code, but it very heavily uses Claude Code&#x27;s capabilities and is not trying to reinvent the wheel and build things that already exist,&quot; Cohen said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   If that sounds a bit like vibe coding, well, that&#x27;s fair to say. But it&#x27;s worth noting that since around November 2025, with the release of Anthropic&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-opus-4-5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    Claude Opus 4.5
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and Google&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/products-and-platforms/products/gemini/gemini-3/#note-from-ceo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    Gemini 3
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and the subsequent release of OpenAI&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    GPT-5.2
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in December 2025, many developers have noticed that the code produced by AI models has gotten quite good.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Vibe coding in other words is starting to look like just coding, without the pejorative adjective attached. A year after
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/karpathy/status/1886192184808149383?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    coining the term &quot;vibe coding,&quot;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   Karpathy this week
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/karpathy/status/2026731645169185220?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    described
   &lt;/a&gt;
   a sea change in the developer community.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;It is hard to communicate how much programming has changed due to AI in the last two months: not gradually and over time in the &#x27;progress as usual&#x27; way, but specifically this last December,&quot; he said. &quot;There are a number of asterisks but [in my opinion] coding agents basically didn&#x27;t work before December and basically work since – the models have significantly higher quality, long-term coherence and tenacity and they can power through large and long tasks, well past enough that it is extremely disruptive to the default programming workflow.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   We asked Cohen how he would quantify the business value of his AI sales chief, citing the concern that many companies have about the potential for damage from unruly software agents.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;What we saw when we connected it to our sales pipeline was that it was doing the work of an employee,&quot; he said. And doing it better than an employee would. I think a lot of people have made this point, but the comparison isn&#x27;t one hundred percent accuracy – that&#x27;s not what we&#x27;re weighing it against. When you work with a colleague, a teammate, an employee, they don&#x27;t get everything right. Things fall through the cracks as well.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   That&#x27;s the level of reliability, Cohen said, that he&#x27;s seen from leading commercial AI models like Opus 4.6 or GPT-5.3 if you have a good &quot;harness&quot; or wrapper (e.g Claude Code or Codex) that gives the model access to tools and allows it to function as an agent.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   NanoClaw builds on work that Anthropic has done with its Agent SDK, and Cohen said it benefits a lot from the kinds of optimizations the company put in place.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   And with NanoClaw&#x27;s sudden popularity, Cohen said that he and his brother have shifted their focus from AI marketing to building the NanoClaw platform.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;I think that what we&#x27;re building can be the orchestration layer that a lot of people are talking about that you need on top of agents,&quot; he said. &quot;That right kind of abstraction nudges people towards using pre-built solid pieces instead of trying to build their own agents. I think it can unlock a lot of value for a lot of businesses, including enterprises that are extremely security conscious.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Cohen added that he hopes the open source community continues to help with NanoClaw. &quot;The project is open source,&quot; he said. &quot;It&#x27;s going to stay open source. We&#x27;re going to keep developing it and building it and making it a great foundation that people can build products and businesses on top of.&quot; ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> French DIY etailer ManoMano admits customer data stolen </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/manomano_breach/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:14:31 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   French online marketplace ManoMano is warning customers their personal data was siphoned off after a cyberattack hit one of its customer support subcontractors – and criminals are already claiming the haul is far larger than the company&#x27;s carefully worded notice suggests.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/shinyhunters_wynn_resorts/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Reflection on surface of Wynn Encore hotel in Las Vegas&quot; height=&quot;115&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2026/02/20/wynn_vegas_reflection.jpg?x=174&amp;amp;y=115&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; width=&quot;174&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;h2 title=&quot;What happens in Vegas…&quot;&gt;
     ShinyHunters demands $1.5M not to leak Vegas casino and resort chain data
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
     READ MORE
    &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In a letter sent to affected users, seen by
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   , ManoMano said it was informed that a customer service provider was hit by a cyberattack in January 2026 that led to &quot;the unauthorized download of personal data associated with your customer account.&quot; The company said its investigation found that &quot;an illegal data extraction was carried out from the account of one of our subcontractor&#x27;s agents.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The exposed data includes first and last names, email addresses, phone numbers, and &quot;any potential exchanges you may have had with our customer service department.&quot; ManoMano stressed that &quot;your password is not affected&quot; and that customer data &quot;remains intact and has not been modified.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ManoMano hasn&#x27;t named the hacked subcontractor, but unconfirmed reports claim the vector for the attack was Zendesk, the widely used –
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/27/scattered_lapsus_hunters_zendesk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    and frequently hacked
   &lt;/a&gt;
   – support platform.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Meanwhile, over on BreachForums, a user calling themselves &quot;Indra&quot; is claiming responsibility for the ManoMano breach and is boasting about a dataset far larger than anything the retailer has publicly confirmed, alleging tens of millions of user records were swept up in the breach.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The actor alleges access to 37.8 million user accounts totaling roughly 43 GB of data, along with 935,000 after-sales service tickets and more than 13,500 attachments. The claimed haul reportedly spans multiple European markets, including France, Spain, Italy, Germany, and the UK.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/wynn_resorts_shinyhunters/&quot;&gt;
     Wynn Resorts takes attacker&#x27;s word for it that stolen staff data was deleted
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/korean_bike_breach_charges/&quot;&gt;
     Korean cops charge teens over bike hire breach that exposed data on 4.62M riders
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/22/cornwall_council_complaints_breach/&quot;&gt;
     UK council faces data breach claim after mishandling trans complaints
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/paypal_app_code_error_leak/&quot;&gt;
     PayPal app code error leaked personal info and a &#x27;few&#x27; unauthorized transactions
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In its notification, the retailer said it &quot;immediately took all necessary measures to protect your data,&quot; blocked the compromised account the same day it was discovered, and &quot;revoked all of our subcontractor&#x27;s access to our customers&#x27; data.&quot; It also reported the incident to France&#x27;s data protection watchdog, CNIL, and the national cybersecurity agency, ANSSI.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The company warned that the stolen information could be used in phishing or impersonation attempts and advised customers to &quot;remain particularly vigilant for potential fraud attempts.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The company is a dedicated third-party marketplace that hooks up DIY and home improvement buyers with verified merchants. It facilitates sales for various sellers across Europe.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   While ManoMano is framing the breach as a subcontractor incident, the alleged scale of the compromise suggests the subcontractor had access to a substantial volume of customer data. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Ransomware payments cratered in 2025, but attacks surged to record highs </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/ransomware_chainalysis/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 08:39:52 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ransomware payments cratered in 2025, but it seems like the cybercrooks launching the attacks didn&#x27;t get the memo.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   That&#x27;s the headline from
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chainalysis.com/blog/crypto-ransomware-2026/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Chainalysis&#x27; 2026 Crypto Crime Report
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , which shows total on-chain ransomware payments falling for a second straight year, even as victim counts and leak site pressure continue to climb.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ransomware gangs pulled in about $820 million in 2025, roughly 8 percent less than the year before, as the share of victims paying dropped to an all-time low of 28 percent. That drop might sound like progress if the wider picture weren&#x27;t so bleak: the median ransom demand jumped from $12,738 in 2024 to $59,556 in 2025, and the number of publicly claimed attacks climbed along with it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Despite the relative stability in total payments, ransomware attacks surged across multiple vectors in 2025, with eCrime.ch data showing a 50 percent YoY increase in claimed ransomware victims, marking the most active year on record,&quot; Chainalysis said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   2025 delivered plenty of high-profile examples of this &quot;most active&quot; year. Jaguar Land Rover
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/15/jlr_payroll_data_stolen_in/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    suffered what&#x27;s been described as the costliest cyber incident in UK history
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/05/ms_pegs_cyberattack_cleanup_costs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Marks &amp; Spencer endured prolonged operational disruption after a Scattered Spider-linked breach
   &lt;/a&gt;
   that wiped hundreds of millions off its market value.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   While 2025 had its share of mega-breaches, the real story is volume. Smaller, opportunistic groups are behind a growing share of extortion attempts, even as the old guard – LockBit, BlackCat, and friends – have been raided, sanctioned, arrested, or simply popped back up under new logos. What&#x27;s left is a crowded field of spin-offs and opportunists taking their chances, and plenty of these incidents never show up as a clean, traceable crypto payout on a blockchain explorer.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/odido_shinyhunters_leaks/&quot;&gt;
     Cops back Dutch telco Odido after second wave of ShinyHunters leaks
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/former_l3harris_exec_jailed/&quot;&gt;
     Ex-L3Harris exec jailed 7 years for selling exploits to Russia
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/wynn_resorts_shinyhunters/&quot;&gt;
     Wynn Resorts takes attacker&#x27;s word for it that stolen staff data was deleted
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/north_koreas_lazarus_group_healthcare_medusa_ransomware/&quot;&gt;
     North Korea&#x27;s Lazarus Group targets healthcare orgs with Medusa ransomware
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Security firm Emsisoft&#x27;s 2025 ransomware data reinforces that picture.
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/08/ransomware_2025_emsisoft/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    More than 8,000 organizations were publicly named on leak sites last year
   &lt;/a&gt;
   – a sharp jump from previous years.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Developed economies are still squarely in the crosshairs. The United States leads the pack yet again, followed by Canada, Germany, the UK, and the rest of Western Europe. Manufacturing, financial, and professional services took plenty of hits, and in Canada and Germany, attackers showed a particular appetite for supply chains, logistics networks, and critical infrastructure. In the US, every major sector – including government and critical infrastructure – saw year-over-year increases in the number of claimed victims.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Chainalysis&#x27;s report also offered a glimpse behind the scenes, where ransomware now looks less like a single criminal enterprise and more like a supply chain.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Initial access brokers (IABs) – the middlemen selling ready-made footholds into corporate networks – received at least $14 million in on-chain payments in 2025. That&#x27;s small compared to ransomware&#x27;s $820 million haul, but Chainalysis found that spikes in IAB payments often precede increases in ransomware payments and US victim leak posts by roughly 30 days. Access gets bought, and a few weeks later, someone&#x27;s name appears on a leak site.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Chainalysis report suggests that ransomware isn&#x27;t shrinking so much as shifting, with fewer victims paying but more organizations getting hit, higher demands, and a thriving access-for-sale marketplace quietly teeing up the next wave of leak-site disclosures. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> SaaS-pocalypse chatter is doomster pr0n. It would be nice if enterprise IT were boring again </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/03/01/saaspocalypse_opinion/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 08:39:50 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Say goodbye to the SaaS-pocalypse theory, which posits that advances in AI will bring the software-as-a-service market to its knees. Say hello to &quot;a feedback loop with no natural brake.&quot; Or doomster porn, as others would have it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   At the beginning of this week, we woke up to a world where
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citriniresearch.com/p/2028gic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    a single tech-related post
   &lt;/a&gt;
   could shake the US stock market and wipe billions of dollars off the value of favorites such as DoorDash and Uber.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to the UK&#x27;s Guardian newspaper, Citrini Research is a little-known US firm that provides insights on &quot;transformative megatrends.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Nonetheless, the firm&#x27;s blog post showed that it could have a big impact by jumping on the SaaS-pocalypse bandwagon and setting off some firecrackers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Loosely, it imagines that the impact of LLM-based AI on the market for SaaS is such that by June 2028, US unemployment will hit 10 percent. Former Salesforce staffers will have to work as Uber drivers. Incumbent application providers will be forced to slash prices.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;SaaS wasn&#x27;t &#x27;dead,&#x27;&quot; points out a fictional commentator from 2028 in the post. &quot;There was still a cost-benefit analysis to running and supporting in-house builds. But in-house was an option, and that factored into pricing negotiations. Perhaps more importantly, the competitive landscape had changed. AI had made it easier to develop and ship new features, so differentiation collapsed. Incumbents were in a race to the bottom on pricing – a knife-fight with both each other and with the new crop of upstart challengers that popped up,&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   More sage commentators were on hand to pour cold water on the wild speculation. Former FT journalist and Evercore ISI analyst Krishna Guha wrote: &quot;Even if the tech and microeconomics were to evolve in line with this scenario, it is highly unlikely that the macro would, as this would require a set of extreme and improbable conditions to hold.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The CEO of cloud-based data warehouse and platform company Snowflake was also on hand to add a bit of sobriety to the SaaS-pocalypse party.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/dsag_ecc_sap/&quot;&gt;
     Half of German-speaking SAP users set to blow past 2027 ECC support deadline
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/workday_q4_2026/&quot;&gt;
     Workday CEO&#x27;s AI talk can&#x27;t shake off weaker sales forecast
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/microsoft_365_roadmap_update/&quot;&gt;
     Microsoft teases &#x27;reimagined SharePoint experience&#x27; with added AI
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/19/worried_about_the_cost_of/&quot;&gt;
     Palantir spent $25M on CEO flights so Alex Karp could do all the talking
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sridhar Ramaswamy said: &quot;It&#x27;s useful to step back and look at the impact that AI as a whole is having on software. We spend a lot of time looking at this. We live this – and our take is that overall, the winners are going to be the companies that provide that single source of enterprise truth. No AI model is going to help you if there are four sources of the truth. Similarly, having built-in security, auditability, trust or even governance over access, who can access what data set is critical.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Speaking to investors, Ramaswamy&#x27;s take was bound to be a bit self-serving. Snowflake wants its platform to be that single source of truth. But he has a point. It is not just the cost of building software that prevents newcomers from taking chunks out of the enterprise software market; it is inertia.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Oracle, Salesforce, and SAP have such an advantage because user data is already in these systems and users are habituated to their processes. Oracle and SAP still have a heavy on-prem footprint, but they are slowly but surely converting customers to SaaS, whether customers want to go there or not. Sure, automation will cut costs, but all the SaaS vendors are already building that automation into their stacks. Gartner says that, at least in the short to medium term,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/16/hyperscales_and_vendor_fund_trillion/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    users will be happy to deploy AI agents from the application environment they already have
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It&#x27;s true that SaaS-only companies may be overvalued. The growth trajectory they have enjoyed in the last decade or so will be unsustainable simply through the law of large numbers. More vendors are entering the market and on-prem vendors are converting customers to SaaS. But businesses and public sector organizations are notoriously slow-moving and risk-averse when it comes to their transactional applications. They need to have the people to make sure it works and that the data is coherent, well-governed, and mostly accurate. It might be boring, but it&#x27;s true. And for now, boring might be the best way to be. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Cops back Dutch telco Odido after second wave of ShinyHunters leaks </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/odido_shinyhunters_leaks/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 06:15:27 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Netherlands&#x27; national police is backing Odido&#x27;s refusal to pay a ransom after ShinyHunters leaked a second round of records belonging to the telco.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In the early hours of Friday morning, the cybercriminals behind ShinyHunters leaked 1 million Odido records for the second day in a row.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Breach/Odido&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Have I Been Pwned
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , which is ingesting the data from each day&#x27;s leaks, the first million contained 317,000 unique email addresses, while the second round consisted of 371,000.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Details associated with those accounts include bank account numbers, other basic personal information, passport numbers, driving licenses, and customer service comments.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ShinyHunters&#x27; website indicates that it is once again gearing up for a third round of leaks on February 28. If this round is of a similar scale, it would push the total number of affected accounts past 1 million.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   After the third round, the cybercrime group promised to begin leaking 2 million records a day. It claims to have stolen around 21 million in total.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Odido first confirmed the scale of the data leak weeks ago, saying
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/13/odido_breach/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    6.2 million customers were affected
   &lt;/a&gt;
   by the attack. The company&#x27;s website is currently not reachable at the time of writing, although the website for subsidiary Ben, whose customers were also caught up in the data theft, is still working.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The telco has also confirmed that it will not be paying a ransom, an unknown sum that
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/wynn_resorts_shinyhunters/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    ShinyHunters
   &lt;/a&gt;
   is demanding to stop the flow of leaked information into the public domain.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Netherlands&#x27; national police (Politie) has reissued an alert advising organizations in similar positions to avoid paying ransoms, just like Odido.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Our advice to ransomware victims is: don&#x27;t pay if criminals demand a ransom,&quot; said Stan Duijf, head of operations responsible for combating cybercrime at the Politie. &quot;After all, if they are paid, their business model remains viable.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/wynn_resorts_shinyhunters/&quot;&gt;
     Wynn Resorts takes attacker&#x27;s word for it that stolen staff data was deleted
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/shinyhunters_wynn_resorts/&quot;&gt;
     ShinyHunters demands $1.5M not to leak Vegas casino and resort chain data
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/18/adidas_investigates_thirdparty_data_breach/&quot;&gt;
     Adidas investigates third-party data breach after criminals claim they pwned the sportswear giant
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/18/shinyhunters_cargurus_breach/&quot;&gt;
     ShinyHunters claims it drove off with 1.7M CarGurus records
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The ultimate decision is up to the victim, but you can&#x27;t assume your data is safe if you pay. We know from
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/02/20/nca_lockbit_takedown/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    research that criminals don&#x27;t always delete the data
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and may resell it or demand more money. If companies are hacked, it&#x27;s crucial that they contact the police as soon as possible, so that together we can limit the damage and secure the evidence.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Politie said Odido was fully complying with its investigation into the attack, and agreed with the company&#x27;s advice to remain vigilant to potential targeted
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/22/crims_compromised_energy_firms_microsoft/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    phishing attacks
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , given the volume of data stolen.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   requested more information from Odido.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The last public statement made by the telco, penned by Søren Abildgaard, CEO at Odido Netherlands, and updated on February 26, said: &quot;Our focus has always been on our customers, and that will remain so.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;On the advice of leading cybersecurity advisors and relevant government agencies, such as the police, Odido has decided not to negotiate with these criminals or allow themselves to be blackmailed by them.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We remain committed to supporting and protecting our customers and employees in the best possible way.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Customers are being offered a 24-month subscription to F-Secure&#x27;s digital security package, which provides protection for devices against malware, phishing, and other threats. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Double whammy: Steaelite RAT bundles data theft, ransomware in one evil tool </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/double_extortion_whammy_steaelite_rat/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 03:12:15 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A new remote access trojan (RAT) being sold on cybercrime networks enables double extortion attacks on Windows machines by bundling ransomware and data theft, along with credential and cryptocurrency stealers, live surveillance, and a whole host of other illicit capabilities, all controllable from a centralized dashboard.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   BlackFog researchers first spotted the malware,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackfog.com/steaelite-rat-double-extortion-from-single-panel/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    called Steaelite
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and touted as &quot;fully undetectable&quot; and the &quot;best Windows RAT,&quot; in November 2025. It works across Windows 10 and 11, with an Android module reportedly in development.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Steaelite&#x27;s operator interface runs entirely in the browser, and the RAT starts stealing victims&#x27; data even before the criminals open the dashboard.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;When a new victim connects, Steaelite automatically harvests browser-stored passwords, session cookies, and application tokens before the operator issues any commands,&quot; according to the AI-based security shop. &quot;Data theft begins at the moment of connection.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The dashboard includes a primary toolbar plus two additional sections, with the primary toolbar alone including modules for remote code execution, file management, live streaming, webcam and microphone access, process management, clipboard monitoring, password recovery, installed program enumeration, location tracking, arbitrary file execution, URL opening, DDoS attacks, and VB.NET payload compilation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   If a criminal is seeking more - like locking up victims&#x27; files and extorting them for cryptocurrency - an &quot;advanced tools&quot; panel includes capabilities for ransomware deployment, hidden RDP, Windows Defender disabling and exclusion management, and persistence installation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Plus, a third &quot;developer tools&quot; panel adds keylogging, client-to-victim chat, file searching, USB spreading, a bot-killing feature that removes competing malware, message box delivery, wallpaper modification, UAC bypass, and a clipper that swaps cryptocurrency wallet addresses during copy-paste operations.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The clipper can silently transfer the victims&#x27; cryptocurrency to the attacker - without the victim ever knowing - by monitoring the clipboard for wallet addresses and replacing them with an attacker-controlled address before the paste completes.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/ransomware_chainalysis/&quot;&gt;
     Ransomware payments cratered in 2025, but attacks surged to record highs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/shinyhunters_wynn_resorts/&quot;&gt;
     ShinyHunters demands $1.5M not to leak Vegas casino and resort chain data
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/19/rmm_rat_trustconnect/&quot;&gt;
     Crims create fake remote management vendor that actually sells a RAT
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/odido_shinyhunters_leaks/&quot;&gt;
     Cops back Dutch telco Odido after second wave of ShinyHunters leaks
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The listing has been bumped consistently across multiple forum threads with 87 messages at the time of writing, and a promotional video demonstrating the tool&#x27;s capabilities has been published on YouTube, a common distribution tactic for commercial remote access trojans looking to reach buyers outside of traditional forum ecosystems,&quot; BlackFog wrote.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In addition to being an all-in-one RAT, this new malware makes it even easier for would-be criminals to pull off double extortion attacks - where the crooks first steal data, then encrypt victims&#x27; systems, and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/odido_shinyhunters_leaks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    threaten to leak the stolen files
   &lt;/a&gt;
   if the victim refuses to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/shinyhunters_wynn_resorts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    pay a ransom
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Previously, double extortion required malware for initial access and exfiltration, then a separate ransomware payload for encryption, often involving coordination between initial access brokers and ransomware affiliates,&quot; BlackFog&#x27;s team wrote. &quot;Steaelite puts both in the same interface, and the automated credential harvesting means data theft fires before the operator even interacts with the dashboard.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Additionally, once the Android version goes live - and assuming it works as planned - a single Steaelite license could cover corporate Windows computers as well as the mobile devices employees use for authentication and messaging, the researchers note. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Suspected Nork digital intruders caught breaking into US healthcare, education orgs </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/suspected_nork_digital_intruders_caught/</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 01:25:10 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Digital intruders with possible links to North Korea have been infecting US education and healthcare sectors with a never-before-seen backdoor since at least December, according to security researchers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We observed that the attacker had infected several educational institutions, including a university that is connected to several other institutions, indicating a potential wider attack surface,&quot; Cisco Talos researcher Chetan Raghuprasad told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   . &quot;Additionally, one of the affected entities was a healthcare facility, specifically for elderly care.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Based on the nature of the victimology in the current intrusions, the actor likely has a motive for financial gain,&quot; Raghuprasad added.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Talos
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.talosintelligence.com/new-dohdoor-malware-campaign/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    spotted the ongoing campaign
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , attributed to a group it tracks as UAT-10027, and says &quot;with low confidence&quot; that it&#x27;s a North Korean crew based on similarities to Lazarus Group and other Pyongyang-backed gangs.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The attackers likely gain initial access via social engineering and phishing, we&#x27;re told, and the multi-stage infection ultimately delivers a new backdoor, Dohdoor, which shares similar technical characteristics to Lazarus Group&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://s2w.inc/en/resource/detail/941&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    Lazarloader
   &lt;/a&gt;
   malware.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   After gaining access - potentially through a phishing email - the intruders execute a PowerShell downloader that runs a Windows batch script dropper from a remote staging server. The batch script then orchestrates a dynamic-link library (DLL) sideloading technique to execute a malicious Windows DLL named &quot;propsys.dll&quot; or &quot;batmeter.dll.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Brand new Dohdoor
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The DLL, which Talos calls &quot;Dohdoor,&quot; operates as a loader, and it downloads, decrypts, and executes malicious payloads within legitimate Windows processes. This gives the intruders backdoor access to the victim&#x27;s environment so it can download the next payload - a Cobalt Strike Beacon - into the machine&#x27;s memory.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   UAT-10027 uses several stealthy techniques to help it avoid detection, including setting up command-and-control (C2) domains using Cloudflare infrastructure and using a technique called DNS-over-HTTPS to resolve the C2 server IP address. This helps the attackers bypass DNS security tools by ensuring all outbound traffic from compromised machines looks like legitimate HTTPS traffic to a trusted IP address.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Dohoor also uses a technique called process hollowing to inject the payload into a legitimate Windows binary, allowing the malware to run without being detected.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Additionally, Talos observed the new backdoor using an endpoint detection and response (EDR) bypass technique to bypass endpoint security tools that monitor Windows API calls. The backdoor does this by by unhooking system calls through user mode hooks in ntdll.dll.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The NTDLL unhooking technique used to bypass EDR monitoring by identifying and restoring system call stubs aligns with features found in earlier Lazarloader variants,&quot; Talos&#x27; researchers Alex Karkins and Chetan Raghuprasad said in a Thursday report.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/north_koreas_lazarus_group_healthcare_medusa_ransomware/&quot;&gt;
     North Korea&#x27;s Lazarus Group targets healthcare orgs with Medusa ransomware
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/09/pyongyangs_cyberspies_are_turning_qr/&quot;&gt;
     QR codes a powerful new phishing weapon in hands of Pyongyang cyberspies
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/18/amazon_blocked_fake_dprk_workers/&quot;&gt;
     Amazon blocked 1,800 suspected North Korean scammers seeking jobs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/01/ai_security_startup_ceo_posts/&quot;&gt;
     AI security startup CEO posts a job. Deepfake candidate applies, inner turmoil ensues
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   They also noted that using DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH) via Cloudflare&#x27;s DNS service, the process hollowing technique, and sideloading malicious DLLs in disguised file name &quot;propsys.dll,&quot; have all been used in earlier Lazarus campaigns.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;While UAT-10027&#x27;s malware shares technical overlaps with the Lazarus Group, the campaign&#x27;s focus on the education and health care sectors deviates from Lazarus&#x27; typical profile of cryptocurrency and defense targeting,&quot; the duo said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   That assertion may be slightly out of date: Symantec and Carbon Black threat hunters earlier this week warned that
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/north_koreas_lazarus_group_healthcare_medusa_ransomware/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Lazarus has begun using Medusa ransomware
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in extortion attacks targeting at least one US healthcare organization.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   One of Lazarus&#x27; most prolific subgroups, Andariel, which acts as the cyber-arm of North Korea&#x27;s military intelligence agency, has previously used
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2022/08/10/maui_ransomware_andariel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Maui
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/north-korean-threat-group-play-ransomware/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Play ransomware
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in its intrusions - including those targeting the healthcare sector. Additionally,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/09/pyongyangs_cyberspies_are_turning_qr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Kimsuky
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , another one of Pyongyang&#x27;s intelligence-gathering goon squads, has hit the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalcyberalliance.org/aide-data-kimsuky/#:~:text=The%20group%20is%20primarily%20targeting,group%27s%20sophisticated%20global%20reconnaissance%20operations&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    education sector
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in its campaigns. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Open source devs consider making hogs pay for every Git pull </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/28/open_source_opinion/</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 08:34:10 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   I&#x27;m at the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.linuxfoundation.org/lf-member-summit/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Linux Foundation Members Summit
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonatype.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Sonatype
   &lt;/a&gt;
   &#x27;s CTO Brian Fox introduced me to a new open source problem. I wouldn&#x27;t have thought that was possible, but here I am.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fox, who also oversees
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://maven.apache.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Apache Maven
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , a popular Java build tool, explained that its repository site is at risk of being overwhelmed by constant Git pulls. The team has dug into this and found that 82 percent of the demand comes from less than 1 percent of IPs. Digging deeper, they discovered that many companies are using open source repositories as if they were content delivery networks (CDNs). So, for example, a single company might download the same code hundreds of thousands of times in a day, and the next day, and the next. This is unsustainable.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   So Maven and other open source repositories are considering introducing a tiered payment system. Lone developers and small groups will still be able to download the code for free, but the hogs will have to pay for every download. In other words, open source software is still free as in speech, but you can forget about being &quot;free as in beer&quot; going forward.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   How bad is it? Fox revealed that last year, major repositories handled 10 trillion downloads. That&#x27;s double Google&#x27;s annual search queries if you&#x27;re counting from home and they&#x27;re doing it on a shoestring. Fox described this as a &quot;tragedy of the commons,&quot; where the assumption of &quot;free and infinite&quot; resources leads to structural waste amplified by CI/CD pipelines, security scanners, and AI-driven code generation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Companies may think that they can rely on &quot;free and infinite&quot; infrastructure, when in reality the costs of bandwidth, storage, staffing, and compliance are accelerating.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fox shared data showing 82 percent of Maven Central&#x27;s consumption comes from less than 1 percent of worldwide IPs, with 80 percent of traffic from the big three hyperscalers. Making it even more troublesome, &quot;IP addresses don&#x27;t represent people. They&#x27;re not even organizations anymore. They&#x27;re ephemeral. They&#x27;re kind of like weather,&quot; Fox explained in an interview, noting challenges from containers, NAT proxies, and cloud egress IPs. In one case, a department store&#x27;s team of 60 developers generated more traffic than global cable modem users worldwide due to misconfigured React Native builds bypassing their Nexus repository manager.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   He detailed extreme examples, such as large organizations downloading the same 10,000 components a million times each month. &quot;That&#x27;s ridiculous,&quot; Fox said. Throttling efforts led to &quot;brownouts&quot; via 429 errors, but patterns mutated, forcing a &quot;Whack-a-Mole&quot; game, especially since most consumption is headless and unnoticed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Registries are also burdened by commercial use, with companies publishing closed source components or massive SDKs as free CDNs. Fox noted that top publishers release gigabyte-scale artifacts daily, unlike in typical open source projects.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In September 2025, the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/23/openssf_open_source_infrastructure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    registries issued an open letter via OpenSSF calling for &quot;tiered access models&quot;
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to keep it free for hobbyists and open source while mandating contributions from high-volume users. &quot;This is the important part, that it has to become mandatory, not optional, &quot; Fox emphasized. Open source charity is not a sustainable model.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Businesses have been treating open source repositories as free, infinite infrastructure. That&#x27;s nonsense. The reality is that the costs of bandwidth, storage, staffing, and compliance are ever-growing. In particular, as the letter stated,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openssf.org/blog/2025/09/23/open-infrastructure-is-not-free-a-joint-statement-on-sustainable-stewardship/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &quot;Commercial-scale use without commercial-scale support is unsustainable
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .&quot; Open source foundations can&#x27;t keep up with the demand for fast dependency resolution, signed packages, zero downtime, and rapid response to supply chain attacks – not to mention looming regulatory requirements such as the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/12/04/infosec_in_brief/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    EU&#x27;s Cyber Resilience Act
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fox anticipates the registries will start rolling out next quarter: &quot;We did the Open Letter way back in October... different ecosystems have figured out models that they think are going to work.&quot; In a pleasant surprise, reactions have been positive. Throttled organizations were &quot;surprised and apologetic,&quot; mistaking issues for malice rather than &quot;ignorance, unawareness.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/open_source_endowment/&quot;&gt;
     New endowment hopes to raise a big pile of money for open source projects
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/veracode_security_ai/&quot;&gt;
     Rapid AI-driven development makes security unattainable, warns Veracode
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/cloudflare_nextjs_api_ai/&quot;&gt;
     Cloudflare experiment ports most of Next.js API &#x27;in one week&#x27; with AI
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/google_android_developer_verification_plan/&quot;&gt;
     Rogue devs of sideloaded Android apps beg for freedom from Google&#x27;s verification regime
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   As the saying goes, never attribute to malice what can be explained by stupidity. Or, as Michael Winser, a co-founder of
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha-omega.dev/about/about-alpha-omega/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Alpha-Omega
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , a Linux Foundation project to help secure the open source supply chain, said at FOSDEM: &quot;If you&#x27;re not caching, you&#x27;re a goddamn idiot.&quot; Amen, brother!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   With AI-driven repository usage exploding, Fox urged checking bills, using caching proxies, and avoiding per-commit tests. He seeks endorsements: &quot;We need you to help step up... so that when we go out to the rest of the wild world... you need to pay to keep doing what you&#x27;ve been doing.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   But, wait, there&#x27;s more! Besides simply being overwhelmed by constant download demands, Winser said, &quot;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/16/open_source_registries_fund_security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    People conflate open source software and open source infrastructure.
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .&quot; Yes, open source software is free, but the cost of registries to host all open source applications and libraries keeps increasing with greater usage.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It&#x27;s not just bandwidth and storage. Winser also pointed out that the repositories &quot;don&#x27;t have enough money to spend on the very security features that we all desperately need to stop being a bunch of idiots and installing fu when it&#x27;s malware.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   To quote Robert A. Heinlein: &quot;There&#x27;s no such thing as a free lunch.&quot; The bill has come due for our misuse of the open source commons. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Trump orders purge of &#x27;woke&#x27; Anthropic from government </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/trump_orders_purge_of_anthropic/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:44:16 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   President Trump has escalated Anthropic&#x27;s dispute with the Defense Department with a social media post ordering the entire federal government purge the company&#x27;s software from its systems.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In a post on Truth Social, the President
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/116144552969293195&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    called
   &lt;/a&gt;
   Anthropic a &quot;radical left, woke&quot; company and said he was directing all federal agencies to cease use of its technology &quot;immediately.&quot; The move comes after a dispute between Anthropic and the Pentagon over the AI firm&#x27;s refusal to relax safeguards barring its models from use in mass domestic surveillance or fully autonomous weapons systems.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The Leftwing nut jobs at Anthropic have made a DISASTROUS MISTAKE trying to STRONG-ARM the Department of War, and force them to obey their Terms of Service instead of our Constitution,&quot; Trump said, apparently referring to the part of the Constitution about spying on Americans with AI and letting autonomous weapons make targeting and firing decisions.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   To be clear,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/pentagon_threatens_anthropic/&quot;&gt;
    neither
   &lt;/a&gt;
   party actually says the Pentagon intend to use Anthropic&#x27;s AI for those purposes, but Anthropic&#x27;s stance was enough to escalate tensions with the Defense Department and raise questions for agencies that had signed up for $1-for-a-year software deals that
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/12/gsa_inks_another_1dollar_onegov_deal/&quot;&gt;
    included
   &lt;/a&gt;
   Anthropic&#x27;s AI.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Trump said in his post that he was giving agencies six months to phase out Anthropic&#x27;s AI for something less woke -
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/25/grokai_servces_us_government/&quot;&gt;
    perhaps
   &lt;/a&gt;
   like
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/09/grok_nazi/&quot;&gt;
    Grok
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/anthropic_claude_opus_3_blog/&quot;&gt;
     Anthropic launches new marketing blog, pretends it&#x27;s being &#x27;written&#x27; by &#x27;retired&#x27; LLM
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/clade_code_cves/&quot;&gt;
     Claude collaboration tools left the door wide open to remote code execution
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/10/trump_wants_no_ai_friction/&quot;&gt;
     Trump to hyperscalers: your datacenters, your power bill
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/06/google_openai_anthropic_us_gov_ai_deal/&quot;&gt;
     Google, OpenAI, Anthropic get blanket deal to saturate US government with their AI
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Anthropic better get their act together, and be helpful during this phase out period, or I will use the Full Power of the Presidency to make them comply, with major civil and criminal consequences to follow,&quot; Trump said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Following the directive, the General Services Administration announced it is removing Anthropic from
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usai.gov/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    USAi.gov
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and its Multiple Award Schedule procurement vehicle.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It&#x27;s not clear what level of official action the President&#x27;s social media is intended to convey. It doesn&#x27;t include any mention of the formal cancellation of Anthropic&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/14/pentagon_ai/&quot;&gt;
    up to $200 million Pentagon contract
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , though we can assume his directive to purge the company from federal systems would mean that the contract is probably void. It appears that, at the very least, the President has no intention of pressing Anthropic to conform to the DoD&#x27;s demands via the Defense Production Act.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   We reached out to Anthropic for comment and to the White House to determine if and when the President intended to issue a formal order
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/opinion/story/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-cancel-culture-charlie-kirk&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    canceling
   &lt;/a&gt;
   Anthropic. We&#x27;ll update this story if we hear back. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters auditioning female voices to sharpen social engineering </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/scattered_lapsus_hunters_female_recruits/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:12:29 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Prolific cybercrime crew Scattered Lapsus$ Hunters (SLSH) is reportedly recruiting women in the hope of improving its social engineering success.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to Telegram channel posts made on February 22, gathered by Dataminr, the group behind last year&#x27;s
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/08/drift_breach_entry_salesloft_github/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Salesloft Drift attacks
   &lt;/a&gt;
   promised payments between $500-$1,000 per call, depending on &quot;success and hit rate.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Interested applicants are invited to apply by sending a message to the group&#x27;s &quot;Support&quot; account. They will be asked a series of questions before being accepted, the group said, and those who pass the test will be given a script to work from.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   SLSH is known for effective
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/21/impersonation_as_a_service/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    social engineering
   &lt;/a&gt;
   . Experts who have listened in on calls carried out by Scattered Spider, one of the groups that form the cybercrime triad, previously confirmed that its tactics are
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/05/18/ex_nsa_scattered_spider_call/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    sophisticated and highly effective
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Telegram ads suggest that SLSH is looking for people to socially engineer IT helpdesk staff. This aligns with the group&#x27;s typical MO of deceiving IT helpdesks into handing over credentials that attackers can use to gain access to an organization&#x27;s network.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;This recruitment drive represents a calculated evolution in SLH&#x27;s tactics,&quot;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dataminr.com/resources/intel-brief/slh-recruiting-women-for-vishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    said
   &lt;/a&gt;
   Jeanette Miller-Osborn, field cyber intelligence officer at Dataminr.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/18/adidas_investigates_thirdparty_data_breach/&quot;&gt;
     Adidas investigates third-party data breach after criminals claim they pwned the sportswear giant
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/18/shinyhunters_cargurus_breach/&quot;&gt;
     ShinyHunters claims it drove off with 1.7M CarGurus records
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/27/shinyhunters_claim_panera_bread/&quot;&gt;
     Let them eat sourdough: ShinyHunters claims Panera Bread as stolen credentials victim
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/08/ransomware_2025_emsisoft/&quot;&gt;
     Ransomware attacks kept climbing in 2025 as gangs refused to stay dead
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;By specifically seeking female voices, the group likely aims to bypass the &#x27;traditional&#x27; profiles of attackers that IT helpdesk staff may be trained to identify, thereby increasing the effectiveness of their impersonation efforts.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Miller-Osborn recommends that organizations make their helpdesks aware of these shifting tactics and ensure identities are thoroughly verified, either through video calls or secondary internal verification.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   SLSH&#x27;s recruitment drive is the latest in what appears to be a trend of crowdsourcing efforts.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Back in October, and again via Telegram, the group said it would
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/06/scattered_lapsus_bitcoin_reward/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    pay anyone $10 in Bitcoin to &quot;endlessly harass&quot; executives
   &lt;/a&gt;
   at organizations it was trying to extort.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;You have permission to endlessly harass these executives till they comply with us,&quot; its message stated. &quot;When we tell you stop emailing a company or number of executives emails, you are to stop emailing them. This will be centralized and well operated.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   When
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   asked SLSH about how many people had taken up its offer after the first few days, it claimed it had &quot;practically paid out over $1,000 at this point,&quot; though these claims cannot be independently verified. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> PCs and phones to get more boring and expensive in 2026 thanks to memory drought </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/memory_drought_pcs_phones_suck/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:12:27 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The next wave of smartphones and PCs will have less memory and fewer capabilities, yet are likely to cost consumers 14 percent more as AI ambitions eat all available memory supplies, according to researchers at IDC.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   IDC said that the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idc.com/resource-center/blog/higher-asps-lower-unit-volumes-how-the-memory-crisis-is-reshaping-the-pc-and-smartphone-outlook/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    worsening memory
   &lt;/a&gt;
   market has caused its outlook to deteriorate just since December. The analysts are penciling in a decline in the PC market of 11.3 percent in 2026 – about 26 percent worse than they had guessed in December – and a decline in the smartphone market of 12.9 percent, which is more than double the 5.2 percent drop they predicted as a worst-case scenario just two months back.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “This is perhaps the biggest challenge the industry has faced since its inception,” said Nabilia Popal, IDC’s senior research director global consumer devices, during a roundtable video discussion posted Thursday. “This is not just a temporary situation. This is going to result in a structural reset of the entire industry, in terms of size, in terms of competitive landscape, of the product mix and also on the price.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   To mitigate the cost and the short supply, IDC expects consumers to hang on to devices longer, or turn to used and refurbished units. Device makers meanwhile are likely to downgrade memory on their least expensive devices, optimize features around using less memory, or in some cases turn to Chinese suppliers that they&#x27;ve avoided over geopolitical or technical concerns.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “Any meaningful impact is expected to take some time,” Jeff Janukowicz, research vice president at IDC, said in a video posted Thursday. &quot;So ultimately, from our perspective we continue to see a challenging environment in 2026. That’s likely to push into 2027.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   IDC is not alone in sounding the alarm. Researchers at
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/memory_price_hikes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Gartner this week
   &lt;/a&gt;
   also said some types of memory have doubled or quadrupled in price since last year, and Gartner believes DRAM and NAND flash used in PCs and phones is set for a further 130 percent rise by the end of 2026.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Gartner is projecting a drop in PC shipments of more than 10 percent during 2026, and a decline of around 8 percent for smartphones, all due to the AI-driven memory shortage.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In the PC market, IDC expects the shortages to begin in the second quarter as smaller vendors struggle to obtain supplies unit volumes will “fall off dramatically,” researchers wrote.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   During its earnings call on Thursday, Dell’s chief operating officer and vice chairman
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.delltechnologies.com/financial-information/quarterly-results&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Jeff Clarke
   &lt;/a&gt;
   said DRAM prices over the last 6 months are up nearly 5.5x, at $2.39 a gigabit. Meanwhile the cost of NAND is $0.20 a gigabyte; that&#x27;s up nearly 4x over the last 6 months. He said that analysts are predicting prices in Q2 to be 20% to 50% higher.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In October, Dell reduced the price of PCs to win market share, then in January, the company increased the cost of PCs to adjust for higher memory prices. At the time, the OEM had tens of thousands of deals in the pipeline that had prices adjusted upwards, which immediately took pressure off Dell’s margins, Clarke said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “In PCs, we purposely delayed implementing that price move to stay in the hunt to take share and to drive growth, which will serve us for the long run,” Clarke said. “And then when we made the change on January 6, it wasn&#x27;t 90 days later, it was that day we stabilized margins,” he said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   During its earnings call this week,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/hp_inc_q1_2026/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    HP revealed
   &lt;/a&gt;
   that memory now accounts for 35 percent of the cost of materials it needs to build a PC, up from between 15 and 18 percent last quarter. The company expects to see memory prices increase 100 percent sequentially into the next quarter, according to HP CFO Karen Parkhill. The company said it has raised PC prices as a result.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/02/dram_prices_expected_to_double/&quot;&gt;
     DRAM prices expected to double in Q1 as AI ambitions push memory fabs to their limit
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/14/dram_infrastructure_costs/&quot;&gt;
     Buy servers now or cry later: DRAM price spike threatens infrastructure budgets
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/20/micron_powerchip_fab_acquisition/&quot;&gt;
     Micron finds a way to make more DRAM with $1.8bn chip plant purchase
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/06/memory_firm_profits_up_as/&quot;&gt;
     Mem-ageddon: AI chip frenzy to wallop DRAM prices with 70% hike
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   And earlier this month
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracast.com/webcasts/lenovo/meetings/7X3Z9C.cfm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Lenovo’s PC boss Luca Rossi
   &lt;/a&gt;
   said that they will raise their average selling price for PCs in 2026, as the number of available PCs will likely drop.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “At the moment, we are modeling a mid-single-digit decline for the units. But that decline will be offset by a higher ASP (average selling price) and likely a favorable product mix,” Rossi told investors on Feb. 12. “Hence, the value of the market will not decline. For Lenovo, we will continue to grow at premium to market.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Janukowicz said with the top four cloud service providers projected to spend $600 billion this year on AI build outs that require DRAM and NAND – some 70 percent more than last year – the cost of memory will likely not stabilize until 2027.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   “This is not necessarily a short disruption and it reflects a structurally tight environment. This is a message that we’ve heard consistently really since the beginning of 2026,” Janukowicz said. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Amazon and Nvidia open their wallets to lock in OpenAI&#x27;s business while SoftBank keeps the lights on </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/amazon_nvidia_softbank_openai_megadeal/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:26:43 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The headlines say OpenAI on Friday announced $110 billion in new investment from Amazon, Nvidia, and SoftBank at a $730 billion pre-money valuation, though terms and conditions apply.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Both Amazon&#x27;s $50 billion and Nvidia&#x27;s $30 billion
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/scaling-ai-for-everyone/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    investments
   &lt;/a&gt;
   are tied to massive customer commitments by OpenAI and its partners.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Of Amazon&#x27;s investment, $35 billion will only be paid out &quot;when certain conditions are met.&quot; From what we gather, those conditions include
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/amazon-partnership/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    renting
   &lt;/a&gt;
   out two gigawatts worth of Amazon&#x27;s Trainium AI accelerators and the deployment of OpenAI models and services in AWS. The cloud provider will also be the &quot;exclusive third-party cloud distribution provider for OpenAI Frontier.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Announced earlier this month, Frontier is OpenAI&#x27;s new
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/introducing-openai-frontier/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    agent builder
   &lt;/a&gt;
   aimed at enterprise customers. Curiously, OpenAI was quick to emphasize that &quot;nothing about today&#x27;s announcements in any way changes the terms of the Microsoft and OpenAI relationship,&quot; and that Azure remains the exclusive cloud provider of its stateless OpenAI APIs and first party products, like Frontier.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Nvidia&#x27;s $30 billion investment appears to have similar provisions. In a
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/scaling-ai-for-everyone/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    blog post
   &lt;/a&gt;
   published on Friday, the AI flag bearer announced an expanded partnership with Nvidia that would see the deployment of three gigawatts of inference and two gigawatts of training capacity built on the GPU slinger&#x27;s Vera Rubin systems. Announced at CES in January, the racks are expected to begin shipping in the second half of 2026.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The economics of datacenters can be tricky to pin down as it varies by region, but at a power usage effectiveness of 1.1, a gigawatt is enough for about 3,600 Vera Rubin NVL72 systems, assuming 250 kW per rack.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   At an
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextplatform.com/ai/2026/01/06/nvidias-vera-rubin-platform-obsoletes-current-ai-iron-six-months-ahead-of-launch/4092179&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    estimated
   &lt;/a&gt;
   cost of $8.4 million each, that&#x27;s roughly $30 billion per gigawatt. However, compute only accounts for about half the cost of standing up a modern AI datacenter.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The land, shell, power, and plumbing costs make up the remainder. This puts the cost of building and deploying 5 gigawatts worth of Vera Rubin accelerators at more than $300 billion. OpenAI is unlikely to take this on itself. Instead, we expect CEO Sam Altman to broker purchase agreements through its hyperscaler and neocloud partners, as it has done with Oracle and Crusoe for its Stargate facility in Abilene, Texas.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Amazon is one of those partners. While OpenAI may be playing up Trainium in today&#x27;s disclosures, its
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/index/aws-and-openai-partnership/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    existing
   &lt;/a&gt;
   $38 billion tie-up with Amazon,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/03/openai_inks_38b_deal_with_aws/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    announced back in November
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , was specific to Nvidia GB200 and GB300 systems. That contract has now been extended to $100 billion over the next eight years.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Both Amazon&#x27;s and Nvidia&#x27;s investments are structured in such a way as to guarantee a return on every dollar invested in OpenAI. The funding is essentially a discount on compute infrastructure that doesn&#x27;t dilute their revenues while driving up OpenAI&#x27;s valuation.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This kind of circular dealing has become commonplace amid the AI boom, and all the big boys are taking part. Back in October, Nvidia rival AMD
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/06/stargate_openai_amd/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    issued
   &lt;/a&gt;
   OpenAI a warrant for roughly 10 percent of its stock. To claim it, all Altman needs to do is deploy six gigawatts of the chip designer&#x27;s Instinct accelerators. This week, AMD
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/amd_copypastes_openai_6gw_chipsforstock/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    copied and pasted
   &lt;/a&gt;
   that deal, extending the same offer to social media and would-be AI magnate Meta.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/burger_kings_new_ai/&quot;&gt;
     Burger King turns to AI to flame broil employees who aren&#x27;t friendly enough
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/nvidia_q4_2026/&quot;&gt;
     Nvidia hasn&#x27;t made a cent in China lately – and might not need to given $120B profit
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/openai_asks_its_friends_to/&quot;&gt;
     OpenAI asks its friends to tell their friends about Frontier
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/sam_altman_ai_efficiency/&quot;&gt;
     Altman: You think AI is wasted energy? Try raising 100 billion humans
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   While Nvidia and Amazon are clearly engaged in financial engineering, the same doesn&#x27;t appear to be the case for SoftBank. Infamous spendthrift Masayoshi Son plans to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://group.softbank/en/news/press/20260227&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    invest
   &lt;/a&gt;
   another $30 billion into the company to keep the lights on while Altman and crew continue their search for artificial general intelligence. SoftBank&#x27;s contribution will be paid out in three tranches of $10 billion beginning in April and wrapping up in October.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Even with annualized recurring revenue reportedly
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/openai-cfo-says-annualized-revenue-crosses-20-billion-2025-2026-01-19/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    exceeding
   &lt;/a&gt;
   $20 billion and more than 50 million paying subscribers on the books, OpenAI is going to be reliant on outside funding for a while. The company isn&#x27;t expected to achieve profitability until at least 2029. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Oak Ridge spawns institute to curb AI datacenter power surge </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/oak_ridge_datacenter_power/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:13:56 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) is hoping to turn its technical expertise to the problem of growing electricity demand from AI datacenters.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The US federal research center in Tennessee is launching the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ornl.gov/nextgendatacenters&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Next Generation Data Centers Institute
   &lt;/a&gt;
   (NGDCI) in support of national energy and AI priorities, though any lessons learned will likely apply globally as well.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   As an internal &quot;institute within an institute,&quot; NGDCI aims to bring together the laboratory&#x27;s facilities and expertise spanning energy, high-performance computing, cybersecurity, and grid technology. The ultimate goal is to ensure that America&#x27;s rapidly growing AI infrastructure remains secure, efficient, and reliable, the lab says.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Artificial intelligence is transforming every part of our society, but its energy appetite is unlike anything we&#x27;ve seen before,&quot; ORNL Director Stephen Streiffer stated.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The electricity required to power AI datacenters is expected to double or triple in the coming decade, straining infrastructure that is already under pressure. ORNL is uniquely positioned to meet this challenge.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Efforts will cover six research areas: thermal management, power system architecture, grid integration, security, integrated systems modeling, and operational load management.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Thermal management will focus on the next generation of cooling tech, as ORNL claims current systems may account for 40 to 60 percent of a datacenter&#x27;s total energy consumption. Research into power system architecture will look at
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/22/ai_power_datacenter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    how energy flows from source to server
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , bringing in ideas such as direct current and new power electronics to reduce losses.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Security considerations will look at embedding
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.gov/ceser/cyber-informed-engineering&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    cyber-informed engineering
   &lt;/a&gt;
   (an actual thing, apparently) into the infrastructure of datacenters, along with quantum-safe communications.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Integrated systems modeling aims to look beyond the walls of the datacenter to anticipate how AI infrastructure may impact energy, jobs, materials, and US competitiveness through the 2030s and beyond.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ORNL says that with the ballooning energy requirements of giant data campuses, the US grid cannot absorb the projected load growth without new approaches to planning and operation. But addressing the problem with intelligent integration that links power, cooling, thermal management, workload scheduling, and AI-enabled forecasting could turn it into an advantage.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/14/x_energy_smr_fuel/&quot;&gt;
     Amazon-backed X-Energy gets green light for mini reactor fuel production
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/17/smr_investment/&quot;&gt;
     All aglow about DCs, investors launch $300M at microreactor startup
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/27/arm_riscv_hpc/&quot;&gt;
     HPC won&#x27;t be an x86 monoculture forever – and it&#x27;s starting to show
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/26/the_exascale_offensive/&quot;&gt;
     The exascale offensive: America&#x27;s race to rule AI HPC
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We envision a future where datacenters are national assets: adaptive, efficient, and strengthening the nation&#x27;s grid while fueling discovery and advancing America&#x27;s leadership in AI,&quot; enthused Robert Wagner, ORNL associate laboratory director for energy science and technology.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Notable names in the AI datacenter arena, including chipmakers Nvidia and AMD, welcomed the move.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;For decades, national labs like ORNL have relied on close collaboration with the computing industry to advance high-performance computing, and the next generation of AI is redefining requirements at the intersection of compute, power, and the grid. NGDCI is designed to address those challenges at scale,&quot; commented Forrest Norrod, the head of AMD&#x27;s Data Center Solutions Business.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ORNL is also part of the &quot;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/doe_genesis_mission_funding/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Genesis Mission
   &lt;/a&gt;
   ,&quot; an initiative launched last year by the Trump administration as a national effort to develop and use AI for scientific discoveries, pooling supercomputers and other facilities from the numerous national labs with resources from industry and academia.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   As part of its contribution, the lab is preparing to deploy the
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/27/hpe_discovery_frontier_successor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Discovery and Lux
   &lt;/a&gt;
   supercomputers. Announced in October, Discovery is set to be a successor to Frontier, the world&#x27;s first exascale system, while Lux is an AI cluster intended to advance machine learning. NGDCI will focus on the technologies required to operate these systems reliably while accelerating scientific breakthroughs, ORNL says. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Microsoft HoloLens finds second home in the military after failing battlefield tests </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/hololens_headsets_pentagon/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:11:13 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The US Army&#x27;s attempt to turn Microsoft HoloLens headsets into battlefield kit may have failed, but the AR goggles aren&#x27;t going into the garbage. Instead, they&#x27;re being repurposed for remote cargo inspection support.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   When it comes to ensuring that pallets of military equipment are properly load-balanced for air transport, there&#x27;s no one better suited to confirm requirements have been met than the US Air Force. Unfortunately, there&#x27;s no way for
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.militaryimages.net/media/sucks.5650/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    delicate
   &lt;/a&gt;
   airmen to be everywhere Army grunts are stuck (this vulture is an Army veteran), and even if they&#x27;re allowed to jump out of airplanes you may not want the average ground-pounder securing cargo that&#x27;s supposed to actually complete its flight.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Faced with that conundrum, the Air Force and Army
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.war.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4416427/hololens-enables-remote-joint-inspection-of-cargo/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;
    teamed up
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to use HoloLens headsets in one of the ways Redmond actually intended, by letting
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2022/01/19/hololens2/&quot;&gt;
    someone qualified
   &lt;/a&gt;
   see through the eyes of a peon.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Members of the 724th Air Mobility Squadron, based in Aviano, Italy, have been working with soldiers from the Army&#x27;s 173rd Airborne Brigade, based in Vicenza, Italy, to give airmen a chance to help soldiers inspect equipment pallets prior to loading onto aircraft.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We spent a year working with the manufacturer [Microsoft] and experimenting with different add-ons to figure out the right software and process we needed to get to where we are today,&quot; said 725th Air Mobility Squadron superintendent, Chief Master Sgt. Anthony Sewejkis. &quot;Now it&#x27;s plug and play. We can connect [from] anywhere just using the HoloLens, a Wi-Fi hotspot and a laptop.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Airmen on laptops were able to see what soldiers were looking at, highlighting areas that needed attention using visual cues to direct soldiers to adjust rigging, reposition cargo, or whatever else needed doing. The augmented reality capabilities afforded to the troops by HoloLens headsets, 724&#x27;s parent org the 521st Air Mobility Operations Wing noted, &quot;increase the speed of maneuver to sustain joint force lethality across the competition continuum.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In other words, they think it&#x27;s pretty cool.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
   Second time&#x27;s a charm?
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The inspection project, which was just a proof of concept but one the Squadron intends to keep refining, was a far greater success than the Army&#x27;s first foray into making use of the HoloLens.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/02/12/microsoft_gives_up_army_ivas/&quot;&gt;
     Microsoft wants to quit building Army VR goggles, hand contract to Anduril
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/05/30/meta_is_now_a_defense/&quot;&gt;
     Meta – yep, Facebook Meta – is now a defense contractor
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/09/us_army_anduril_headset/&quot;&gt;
     US Army straps on another mixed-reality gamble with Anduril, Rivet
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/27/salesforce_5b_deal_agentic_ai_us_army/&quot;&gt;
     Salesforce signs $5.6B deal to inject agentic AI into the US Army
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It all started back in 2018, when the Army awarded Microsoft a contract to build the Integrated Visual Augmentation System (IVAS) - custom HoloLens-derived headsets meant to give soldiers a battlefield heads-up display. Despite a deal described as worth up to nearly $22 billion over a decade,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2022/10/13/us_army_report_microsoft_hololens/&quot;&gt;
    testing didn&#x27;t go smoothly
   &lt;/a&gt;
   . A Pentagon watchdog report found the goggles caused “mission-affecting physical impairments,” including headaches, eyestrain, and nausea, among many of the soldiers who tested them.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Attempts to continue the program, by dumping millions more into it, were met with resistance from Congress, which
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/01/12/congress_hololens_microsoft/&quot;&gt;
    slashed funding
   &lt;/a&gt;
   for the program. Microsoft ultimately
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/02/12/microsoft_gives_up_army_ivas/&quot;&gt;
    gave up
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , passing control of the initiative to Oculus inventor Palmer Luckey&#x27;s Anduril. Anduril in turn
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/05/30/meta_is_now_a_defense/&quot;&gt;
    brought Meta
   &lt;/a&gt;
   into the mix before the Army ultimately relaunched the program under a new name as the Soldier Borne Mission Command (SBMC) program, with the intention of developing an entirely new headset that hopefully isn&#x27;t such a headache for soldiers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It doesn&#x27;t help for Microsoft&#x27;s prospects as a supplier of military mixed reality headsets that the company
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/02/microsoft_hololens_2_dead/&quot;&gt;
    canned development of the HoloLens
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in late 2024, with support for existing models slated to run through the end of 2027.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It&#x27;s not clear whether the headsets used in the cargo loading experiment were leftovers from IVAS, discounted leftovers acquired by the Air Force, or if they were purchased specifically for the project. We reached out to the Army and Air Force to learn more, but didn&#x27;t hear back. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Moon&#x27;s mighty magnetic field was a 5,000-year titanium blip </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/moon_magnetic_field/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:21:46 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Scientists at the University of Oxford say they may have cracked the puzzle of the Moon&#x27;s magnetic field and settled a debate that has raged since the Apollo missions returned with rock samples.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   NASA astronauts brought back evidence suggesting the lunar magnetic field was strong for long periods of its history, at times even stronger than Earth&#x27;s.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The findings created a puzzle, though. Scientists also considered the theory that the relatively small size of the Moon&#x27;s core – around one-seventh of its radius – means it cannot create a strong field.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   New research from Oxford&#x27;s Department of Earth Sciences shows they are both right... kind of.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Led by associate professor Claire Nichols, the team analyzed the composition of a type of lunar rock known as the Mare basalts and found a new correlation between their titanium content and levels of magnetism.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Looking at the collected lunar samples, they found those with a strong magnetic field also contained large amounts of titanium, but those with less than 6 percent titanium were all associated with a weak magnetic field.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The study argues that the formation of high-titanium rocks and a strong lunar magnetic field were the result of titanium-rich material melting deep inside the Moon, which created a strong magnetic field, but only for about 5,000 years.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Our new study suggests that the Apollo samples are biased to extremely rare events that lasted a few thousand years – but up to now, these have been interpreted as representing 0.5 billion years of lunar history. It now seems that a sampling bias prevented us from realizing how short and rare these strong magnetism events were,&quot; she said in a statement.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/19/nasa_starliner_blame/&quot;&gt;
     NASA points fingers at Boeing and chaotic culture for Starliner debacle
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/13/moon_hotel_startup_reservation/&quot;&gt;
     Moon hotel startup hopes you get lunar lunacy, drop $1M deposit for 2032 stay
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/09/spacex_resumes_falcon_9/&quot;&gt;
     SpaceX back to Falcon 9 launches as Musk blathers about Moon city
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/06/smartphones_nasa/&quot;&gt;
     Smartphones cleared for launch as NASA loosens the rulebook
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We now believe that for the vast majority of the Moon&#x27;s history, its magnetic field has been weak, which is consistent with our understanding of dynamo theory. But that for very short periods of time – possibly as short as a few decades – melting of titanium-rich rocks at the Moon&#x27;s core-mantle boundary resulted in the generation of a very strong field.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The research team said Mare basalts made a good landing site for the Apollo missions because they are relatively flat. Since the astronauts brought back nearby rocks, they carried more titanium-rich basalts than a representative sample of the Moon&#x27;s surface would have. The result was a false impression of the length of time during which the Moon had a strong magnetic field.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Co-author Dr Simon Stephenson added: &quot;We are now able to predict which types of samples will preserve which magnetic field strengths on the Moon. The upcoming Artemis missions offer us an opportunity to test this hypothesis and delve further into the history of the lunar magnetic field.&quot; ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Lovable-hosted app littered with basic flaws exposed 18K users, researcher claims </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/lovable_app_vulnerabilities/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:58:20 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Vibe-coding platform Lovable has been accused of hosting apps riddled with vulnerabilities after saying users are responsible for addressing security issues flagged before publishing.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Taimur Khan, a tech entrepreneur with a background in software engineering, found 16 vulnerabilities – six of which he said were critical – in a single Lovable-hosted app that leaked more than 18,000 people&#x27;s data.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   He declined to name the app during the disclosure process, although it was hosted on Lovable&#x27;s platform and showcased on its Discover page. The app had more than 100,000 views and around 400 upvotes at the time Khan began his probe.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The main issue, Khan said, was that all apps that are vibe-coded on Lovable&#x27;s platform are shipped with their backends powered by Supabase, which handles authentication, file storage, and real-time updates through a PostgreSQL database connection.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   However, when the developer – in this case AI – or the human project owner fails to explicitly implement crucial security features like Supabase&#x27;s row-level security and role-based access, code will be generated that looks functional but in reality is flawed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   One example of this was a malformed authentication function. The AI that
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/24/opinion_column_vibe_coding/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    vibe-coded
   &lt;/a&gt;
   the Supabase backend, which uses remote procedure calls, implemented it with flawed access control logic, essentially blocking authenticated users and allowing access to unauthenticated users.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Khan said the intent was to block non-admins from accessing parts of the app, but the faulty implementation blocked all logged-in users – an error he said was repeated across multiple critical functions.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;This is backwards,&quot; said Khan. &quot;The guard blocks the people it should allow and allows the people it should block. A classic logic inversion that a human security reviewer would catch in seconds – but an AI code generator, optimizing for &#x27;code that works,&#x27; produced and deployed to production.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Because the app itself was a platform for creating exam questions and viewing grades, the userbase is naturally comprised of teachers and students. Some were from top US universities such as UC Berkeley and UC Davis, while there were &quot;K-12 institutions with minors likely on the platform&quot; as well, Khan
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/lovable-more-like-hackable-taimur-khan-cewdf/?trackingId=%2BscO7NGeQ0%2BpVd7b1U0fYA%3D%3D&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    said
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   With the security flaws in place, an unauthenticated attacker could trivially access every user record, send bulk emails through the platform, delete any user account, grade student test submissions, and access organizations&#x27; admin emails, for example.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Of the 18,697 total user records exposed, 14,928 contained unique email addresses. The dataset included 4,538 student accounts – all with email addresses – 10,505 enterprise users, and 870 users whose full PII was exposed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The security flaws here are not exclusive to apps hosted by Lovable; the issue is broader and well-told by now.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Vibe coding, Collins Dictionary&#x27;s Word of the Year for 2025, promised to break down software development&#x27;s steep learning curve and empower any prompt jockey to bring their app ideas to life.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   However, when AI isn&#x27;t
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/21/curl_ends_bug_bounty/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    generating slop bug reports
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in pursuit of lucrative bug bounties or
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/21/replit_saastr_vibe_coding_incident/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    catastrophically forgoing instructions
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , it can be found spewing glitzy-looking apps laden with vulnerabilities.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/bcachefs_creator_ai/&quot;&gt;
     Bcachefs creator insists his custom LLM is female and &#x27;fully conscious&#x27;
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/ibm_share_dive_anthropic_cobol/&quot;&gt;
     IBM stock dives after Anthropic points out AI can rewrite COBOL fast
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/amazon_denies_kiro_agentic_ai_behind_outage/&quot;&gt;
     Amazon&#x27;s vibe-coding tool Kiro reportedly vibed too hard and brought down AWS
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/19/jon_kern_vibe_coding/&quot;&gt;
     Agile Manifesto turns 25 – just in time for vibe coding to test it
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Veracode, for instance,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracode.com/blog/ai-generated-code-security-risks/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    recently found
   &lt;/a&gt;
   that 45 percent of AI-generated code contained security flaws, not to mention the myriad
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/05/mcpoison_bug_abuses_cursor_mcp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    tales
   &lt;/a&gt;
   of
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/openclaw_snuck_into_cline_package/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    woe
   &lt;/a&gt;
   reported by
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   in recent months.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Khan said he believes Lovable should take responsibility for the security of the apps it hosts, and was especially peeved when, after reporting his findings via company support, his ticket was reportedly closed without response.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;If Lovable is going to market itself as a platform that generates production-ready apps with authentication &#x27;included,&#x27; it bears some responsibility for the security posture of the apps it generates and promotes,&quot; Khan said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;You can&#x27;t showcase an app to 100,000 people, host it on your own infrastructure, and then close the ticket when someone tells you it&#x27;s leaking user data. At minimum, a basic security scan of showcased applications would have caught every critical finding in this report.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Lovable told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   that the company has contacted the owner of the app in question and takes &quot;any findings of this kind extremely seriously.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Regarding the closed ticket, Lovable CISO Igor Andriushchenko said that the company only received &quot;a proper disclosure report&quot; on the evening of February 26 and acted on the findings &quot;within minutes.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Any project built with Lovable includes a free security scan before publishing,&quot; Andriushchenko told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   . &quot;This scan checks for vulnerabilities and, if found, provides recommendations on actions to take to resolve before publishing.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Ultimately, it is at the discretion of the user to implement these recommendations. In this case, that implementation did not happen.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;This project also includes code not generated by Lovable and the vulnerable database is not hosted by Lovable. We have been in contact with the creator of the app, who is now addressing the issue.&quot; ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Japan&#x27;s Rapidus lands $1.7B to chase 2nm chip production by 2027 </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/rapidus_funding/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:36:01 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Japan&#x27;s fledgling foundry biz Rapidus has secured funding of $1.7 billion to help it progress to mass production of 2nm semiconductors by 2027, making it a potential rival for Taiwan&#x27;s TSMC.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The startup silicon manufacturer has completed a funding round delivering ¥267.6 billion (equivalent to $1.7 billion) from the Japanese government and private sector companies.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ¥100 billion of the funding came from the Information-technology Promotion Agency (IPA), an independent administrative body under the jurisdiction of the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI).
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The remaining ¥167.6 billion has been sourced from 32 companies including Canon, Fujitsu, NTT, SoftBank, Development Bank of Japan, and Sony Group.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rapidus was founded in 2022 with the aim of revitalizing Japan&#x27;s fading semiconductor industry, and has signed up help from IBM and Belgian-based R&amp;D organization
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/06/05/asml_imec_high_na_euv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Imec
   &lt;/a&gt;
   (Interuniversity Microelectronics Center) for the development of the technology required to reach its goal.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   IBM claimed to be the first company in the world to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2021/05/06/ibm_2nm_semiconductor_chips/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    show off 2nm chips
   &lt;/a&gt;
   back in 2021, and was also the first to show 5nm and 7nm wafers previously, although it does not have the facilities to mass produce them itself.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rapidus said it will continue to secure funding through capital increases and loans from both public and private sources. It believes this strategic funding plan will enable it to progress from its current R&amp;D phase through to mass production of 2nm silicon by 2027.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This is an ambitious plan for a four-year-old firm and could position Rapidus as a rival to chipmaking giants
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/16/tsmc_q4_2025/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    TSMC
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/06/29/samsung_foundry_roadmap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Samsung
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , both of which started volume production using their own 2nm silicon processes in Q4 of 2025.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/07/18/rapidus_foundry_2nm/&quot;&gt;
     Foundry competition heats up as Japan&#x27;s Rapidus says 2nm chip tech on track for 2027
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/09/09/rapidus_government_funding/&quot;&gt;
     Rapidus, rapidly running through funds, needs $700M for 2nm chip plant
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/09/01/rapidus_hiring_fab/&quot;&gt;
     Rapidus ramps as construction begins on 2nm wafer fab
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/07/18/samsung_tsmc_processor_plans/&quot;&gt;
     Samsung &#x27;closing the gap&#x27; with TSMC on 3nm, 4nm
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It is unlikely to be able to match either of those established manufacturers on volume, at least in the early days, but could prove a valuable extra foundry for chip designers looking to get cutting-edge silicon products made.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to Japanese newspaper
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://mainichi.jp/english/articles/20260227/p2g/00m/0bu/057000c&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    The Mainichi
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , the country&#x27;s government has now become the largest shareholder in Rapidus, holding 11.5 percent of its voting rights, as well as holding a &quot;golden share&quot; giving it veto power over key management decisions.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;It is a key element of the investments for growth promoted by the government and a national project that must succeed for the sake of the country&#x27;s interests,&quot; it quotes the minister for economy, trade and industry Ryosei Akazawa as saying.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fujifilm, one of the companies contributing to the latest investment, said it is committed to realizing the domestic mass production of leading-edge semiconductors and to the development of Japan&#x27;s semiconductor industry.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The firm, a supplier of semiconductor raw materials, stated it will support Rapidus by providing a range of technologies and will work closely with it on next-generation process development. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> 50 GW of datacenter demand queues up for UK grid access </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/datacenter_uk_grid_demand/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:21:49 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   About 140 datacenters are in the queue to be connected to Britain&#x27;s power grid, and their combined energy requirements are estimated to be more than the current peak electricity use for the entire country.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ofgem, the energy regulator for England, Scotland, and Wales, recently published a call for input on
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofgem.gov.uk/sites/default/files/2026-02/2026-02-12-Demand-Connections-Call-for-Input.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Demand Connections Reform
   &lt;/a&gt;
   [PDF], inviting views from interested parties on how to improve the demand connections process.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The problem faced is that the demand queue is large and growing, and is said to contain a significant number of projects that are &quot;likely non-viable.&quot; At the same time, viable projects are being held up because of the length of time needed for network or generation building.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The document claims these issues are exacerbated because there are no mechanisms to prioritize strategically important demand projects.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   For &quot;strategically important projects,&quot; read &quot;datacenters.&quot; The UK government unveiled its
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/13/uk_government_ai_plans/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    AI Opportunities Action Plan
   &lt;/a&gt;
   last year, aimed at driving economic recovery, and this includes the establishment of &quot;AI Growth Zones&quot; with streamlined planning processes to encourage the rapid building of more datacenters.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ofgem says that since November 2024, total contracted offers in the demand queue rose sharply from 41 GW to 125 GW by June 2025. It contrasts this with the peak electricity use in Britain on February 11 this year, which stood at 45 GW.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A call for input from the National Energy System Operator (NESO), which manages and plans the country&#x27;s electricity and gas systems, found that a significant portion of those projects in the demand queue are datacenters. It identified about 140 facilities, the majority of which are likely to receive a Gate 2 offer, which is a &quot;ready-to-connect&quot; agreement, and these add up to a total of 50 GW of demand for electricity.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   These are not likely to all be connected at the same time, of course, as many are in the early stages of construction or still being planned.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   But it isn&#x27;t just that these server farms are being held up. There is also the question of extra grid and generating capacity. Ofgem says that demand-side projects are only required to meet &quot;readiness&quot; criteria under the Connections Reform Package (TMO4+) introduced last year, unlike generation, storage, and interconnection projects that must be &quot;ready&quot; and &quot;needed&quot; under the Clean Power 2030 Action Plan.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Ofgem states that it, the government and NESO are together taking a phased approach to reforming demand connections. This starts with immediate measures to strengthen financial commitments and weed out non-viable datacenters in the demand queue and prioritize strategic projects.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A second phase will see further measures to implement a strategic plan for data facilities, alongside additional measures to strengthen project commitments and address non-viable demand projects, Ofgem says.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   We must confess to being puzzled, since we recall Ofgem announcing new rules some time ago aimed at speeding up electricity grid connections for viable projects and pushing stalled or speculative developers out of the queue. We asked the regulator if it could clarify the situation, and will update if we get an answer.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Omdia principal analyst for Colocation and DC Building Alan Howard told us that the power interconnection queue issue is a big problem, not just in the UK, but also in the US and other global markets.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The strategy for many datacenter operators is to secure multiple land parcel rights, request a grid load connection for each (often requiring a costly load study), and see what gets approved so they can build. The capital investment to take all these projects seriously is clearly untenable and a huge financial risk for the energy sector if the demand doesn&#x27;t fully materialize,&quot; he said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/nutanix_q2_2026/&quot;&gt;
     AMD puts $250M into Nutanix to get it building an AI stack for its GPUs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/nvidia_q4_2026/&quot;&gt;
     Nvidia hasn&#x27;t made a cent in China lately – and might not need to given $120B profit
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/ai_chips_vc_funding_1point1billion/&quot;&gt;
     It&#x27;s only Tuesday and AI chip startups have already soaked up $1.1B in funding
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/24/amd_copypastes_openai_6gw_chipsforstock/&quot;&gt;
     AMD copy-pastes 6 GW chips-for-stock deal in new Meta agreement
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This was highlighted in a
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/08/uptime_institute_datacenter_grid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    report from Uptime Institute
   &lt;/a&gt;
   last year, which found that developers try to reserve power for projects that may never be built, while datacenter operators apply for more than they need to accommodate future growth and planning uncertainty.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The Ofgem Demand Connections Reform initiative is a great idea whereby an evidence-based system would be created to weed out or deprioritize the inevitable non-viable datacenter projects,&quot; Howard said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Using evidence such as a Final Investment Decision (FID) to show financing commitment or the ability to secure project planning permission from regulators would prioritize projects that are in the best interest of communities and the energy ecosystem at large.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The government also instituted an &quot;AI Energy Council&quot; when it launched the AI Opportunities Action Plan, in order to address the growing energy demands from all those AI facilities. This comprises Ofgem and NESO, along with energy companies and some of the big datacenter operators – Google, AWS, Microsoft and Equinix.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   We asked what the AI Energy Council is doing to ensure there will be enough energy to meet all this anticipated demand from new datacenters.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A spokesperson for the Department for Energy Security and Net Zero (DESNZ) told us: &quot;Datacenters will only be connected where the grid can support them. The AI Energy Council is exploring opportunities to attract investment in new clean power sources for the industry, as we work with Ofgem and network companies to free up grid capacity.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Our AI Growth Zones are driving their development in areas with new clean power generation such as North Wales, the home of our first small modular reactors,&quot; the spokesperson added.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The small modular reactor (SMR) was
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/13/anglesey_smr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    announced last year
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , and will be sited at Wylfa on Anglesey, an island off northwest Wales, but it won&#x27;t generate power until the mid-2030s.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Earlier this month, the government unveiled an Advanced Nuclear Framework initiative to attract private investment into next-generation nuclear technology to power factories and datacenters.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   We understand there are currently five AI Growth Zones across England, Scotland, and Wales, including one recently announced in North Lanarkshire and one at the Culham Science Centre (UKAEA) in Oxfordshire. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Sopra Steria sues UK government over £958M Capita outsourcing award </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/sopra_steria_sues_ukgov/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:51:59 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sopra Steria is suing the UK government, alleging it accepted a bid from rival Capita for an outsourcing contract worth up to £958.7 million that it failed to recognize as too low to comply with procurement rules.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In court filings accessed by
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   , the French outsourcer claims the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP), which leads the shared services program for multiple departments, failed to spot that Capita&#x27;s bid for the contract was &quot;abnormally low&quot; relative to Sopra Steria&#x27;s tender for the same work.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It also alleges that after the UK outsourcer was named preferred bidder for the contract, the DWP conducted further renegotiations around Capita&#x27;s tender. Sopra Steria argues it was excluded from any such process.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A DWP spokesperson said: &quot;We are aware of the legal challenge and are cooperating fully with the relevant processes. As this matter is currently subject to litigation, it would be inappropriate to comment further at this time. Our priority is to ensure continuity of service and value for money for the public.&quot; Capita declined to comment.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Public and Commercial Services (PCS) Union this week claimed Capita&#x27;s winning bid was £700 million. The contact award, which will see Capita handling payroll for 250,000 civil servants, was criticized by the union.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   has asked Capita and the DWP to confirm the size of the bid accepted.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The DWP told us: &quot;We have delivered a robust procurement process, in line with Government procurement regulations to identify a preferred bidder for the Synergy BPS contract.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We stand ready to work with the successful bidder to ensure a smooth transition of service. Our priority remains to ensure continuity of service and value for money for the public.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The DWP leads the Synergy program, intended to transfer it, the Ministry of Justice (MoJ), the Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (Defra), and the Home Office to one SaaS ERP and HR system with a common set of business processes.
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.find-tender.service.gov.uk/Notice/030687-2024&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Oracle and IBM have already won
   &lt;/a&gt;
   the contract for ERP technology and systems integration as part of a single £711 million deal.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sopra Steria is the incumbent provider for three of these departments&#x27; shared service, the Oracle EBS-based Single Operating Platform, run by SSCL, which the French company owns. The Home Office is not part of that shared service, but SSCL also supports the department and moved it from EBS to Fusion in 2021.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In September 2024,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/09/18/dwp_business_processes_procurement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    the DWP launched the competition
   &lt;/a&gt;
   for a supplier to develop and run business process services (BPS) for the Synergy departments, under a contract set to be worth up to £958.7 million for ten years, including extensions.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The tender said the BPS contract would &quot;deliver modern and innovative value for money services which maximize positive user experience.&quot; It added: &quot;The BPS supplier will also be challenged to continuously evolve, improve, and optimize service delivery over the course of the contract.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to the legal papers filed by Sopra Steria, in December 2025, the DWP confirmed it had been unsuccessful in the procurement and that Capita had won the tender.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The legal papers allege, based on information Sopra Steria claims it received: &quot;Capita was not able to satisfy the requirements&quot; set out in the selection process because of its &quot;limited business in payroll and HR services&quot; and because it could provide &quot;few examples of design, deployment and operation of BPS Services running on... an Oracle SaaS ERP&quot; system.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Following correspondence between the DWP and Sopra Steria, the government department provided an assessment of Capita&#x27;s bid, which the outsourcing vendor alleges in the legal filing shows Capita&#x27;s implementation service charges were &quot;assessed as appearing abnormally low&quot; as of July 2025. The DWP then made two requests for clarification, one in August 2025, which was issued after the evaluation end date, Sopra Steria alleges. Following this clarification process, Capita&#x27;s bid was determined to be &quot;not abnormally low.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The legal claim also alleges that Capita&#x27;s pricing implies &quot;Capita&#x27;s proposed staffing solution is significantly below the current staffing levels for the BPS service, and that proposed by the [DWP]. Such low staffing levels raise serious and legitimate concerns as to the ability of Capita to provide the Synergy BPS in line with the [DWP&#x27;s] requirements, both in themselves and in conjunction with the apparently low level of technology investment from Capita.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The claim also alleges that the DWP, Oracle, and IBM discussed a change request to their project, which included consolidation of go-live dates across Synergy departments, postponing go-live dates and altering parts of the solution.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The DWP decided to renegotiate Capita&#x27;s tender to help it align with this change request after the outsourcing company&#x27;s selection as preferred bidder, Sopra Steria&#x27;s particulars of claim allege. &quot;Such renegotiation of the tender and/or amendment to the Synergy Contract is in breach of&quot; the DWP&#x27;s obligations under the procurement rules, the claim alleges.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/saaq_sap_overrun/&quot;&gt;
     Quebec vehicles agency spent C$245M over budget on SAP ERP it wasn&#x27;t sure it needed
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/06/west_sussex_oracle/&quot;&gt;
     UK council digs deeper into capital assets to keep Oracle project afloat
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/05/sap_migrations_research/&quot;&gt;
     Most SAP migrations bust budgets and project timelines, research finds
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/29/birmingham_oracle_latest/&quot;&gt;
     Birmingham City Council&#x27;s Oracle ERP fiasco now £144M and still not working
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/17/capita_microsoft_copilot_pensions/&quot;&gt;
     Capita taps Microsoft Copilot to dig it out from UK pensions backlog
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sopra Steria wants the court to terminate and/or rerun the procurement process. It is also asking for damages. No date has been set for the hearing, pending requests to assess further commercially sensitive information.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Regardless of its merit, the claim comes at a difficult time for Capita. It was forced to defend its performance in
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/29/capita_pension_portal_update/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    the Civil Service Pension Scheme
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , which has seen a string of complaints from members.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In a statement issued this week, the PCS called the DWP contract award to Capita a &quot;reckless gamble.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   PCS general secretary Fran Heathcote said: &quot;Capita is already at the center of a pensions crisis that has left retired civil servants in distress. Privatization is a failure, so why does the government continue to reward those responsible with yet another massive public contract?&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The DWP will also want to avoid a legal case derailing progress on Synergy. In 2021,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2021/03/29/moj_cancels_100m_erp_procurement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    the Ministry of Justice cancelled its ERP upgrade project
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to get in step with the wider program. Delays could jeopardize the goodwill needed to change people&#x27;s working processes. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Mondelēz picks Celonis as process backbone for SAP overhaul </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/mondelez_sap_migration_celonis/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:26:33 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   In the middle of a mammoth migration off SAP&#x27;s legacy ERP systems, global snack giant Mondelēz has found an alternative to the German vendor&#x27;s tech as the main platform for understanding its complex, fragmented business processes.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The maker of Oreo cookies, Cadbury&#x27;s chocolate, and Toblerone began moving its diverse ERP estate from ECC to S/4HANA two years ago, and is using a Celonis platform to model business processes after trying out SAP&#x27;s technology, CIO Rossana Rizzotto told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/airbus_exec_sap/&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Cloud migration&quot; height=&quot;115&quot; src=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2020/12/21/shutterstock_cloud_migration.jpg?x=174&amp;amp;y=115&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; width=&quot;174&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;h2 title=&quot;Aerospace giant faces &#x27;massive work&#x27; to move legacy ERP systems to S/4HANA as support deadline looms&quot;&gt;
     Airbus exec: Most CIOs in Europe will not finish SAP ECC6 migration by 2030
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
     READ MORE
    &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Mondelēz has annual revenue of around $38.5 billion, 91,000 employees, and operations in around 80 countries. It was divested from Kraft Foods in 2011 and has also grown through acquisition, for example, by snapping up one of the UK&#x27;s favorite chocolate makers, Cadbury. As a result, its ERP migration involved understanding processes that might be fragmented, decentralized, and varied in maturity.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The move from ECC to S/4HANA is more than a technical migration; users end up on a completely different platform and usually adopt a more standardized set of business processes on the way.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Mondelēz and its acquired companies had also customized their ECC systems. As part of the project, the company wants to make processes more efficient, review its outsourcing models, and create business growth. And it wants to lay the foundations for adopting agentic AI.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   To get to grips with the problem, Rizzotto&#x27;s team was looking to make greater sense of existing business processes. As a result, it was exploring process mining, which works by pulling together data from user interactions with enterprise applications and analyzing them in an attempt to reveal the &quot;true&quot; nature of business processes, as opposed to how they were designed or how management thinks they are performed.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rizzotto told us Mondelēz decided against adopting SAP&#x27;s process mining tool – Signavio, which it acquired in 2021 – for a technology independent of the main enterprise application vendor.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We have a strategic partnership with SAP. In the past, we have used pockets of Signavio. We want to be agnostic as much as we can [and use] the capability of Celonis to connect with our landscape, which is ERP SAP-based, but also goes beyond SAP,&quot; she told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Founded in 2011 as a college project for consulting businesses, Celonis cut its teeth looking at processes at German engineering giant Siemens and its complex estate of SAP ERP systems.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We started with Celonis with our initial use case at the back end of 2024. In July 2025, we made the decision to embrace it as a strategic enterprise platform,&quot; Rizzotto said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Mondelēz is adopting the Celonis Process Intelligence Platform, which the vendor says combines data from customer systems, applications, and devices to build a &quot;living digital twin&quot; of operations. The CIO said it was impressed by the way it could map processes across ERP systems, but also the wider application landscape.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Celonis has this tremendous capability to connect the very composite landscape with standard APIs. At the beginning, our ambition is to create a digital twin of the enterprise, which enables us to mirror all of our processes and capabilities in a digital way,&quot; Rizzotto said.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Mondelēz is applying process intelligence to some of its key end-to-end processes, including offshore services, in-house operations, and outsourced services. This is being applied across source-to-pay, order-to-cash, record-to-report, and hire-to-retire.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It has already connected the platform with its top 25 transactional systems of record and is also using a &quot;process conformity platform&quot; to contextualize training and drive adoption based on technology from WalkMe, which is owned by SAP.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The snack maker also hopes Celonis will lay the groundwork for adopting agentic AI, although the jury is still out on which technology providers are best for deploying AI agents.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Tech vendors are vying for control of this emerging technology. Application vendors see AI agents sitting within their technology – SAP, Salesforce, and Workday all have a pitch here – and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/16/hyperscales_and_vendor_fund_trillion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Gartner says
   &lt;/a&gt;
   many users will see that as a short-term, low-risk option. However, hyperscalers such as
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/27/aws_ai_agent_saas/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    AWS want to provide agentic AI platforms to work across a portfolio of enterprise applications
   &lt;/a&gt;
   from different vendors.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/saaq_sap_overrun/&quot;&gt;
     Quebec vehicles agency spent C$245M over budget on SAP ERP it wasn&#x27;t sure it needed
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/05/sap_migrations_research/&quot;&gt;
     Most SAP migrations bust budgets and project timelines, research finds
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/12/11/airbus_exec_sap/&quot;&gt;
     Airbus exec: Most CIOs in Europe will not finish SAP ECC6 migration by 2030
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/19/kingfisher_sap/&quot;&gt;
     SAP&#x27;s migration narrative suddenly looks messy as Kingfisher goes off-script
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rizzotto said: &quot;We are leveraging the embedded AI engine of Celonis to enable not just the mining activity, but also to rebuild in Celonis our business process knowledge. We&#x27;re also looking at the technology landscape that best supports the agentic landscape that we want to either adopt ourselves or through strategic providers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The world is very much moving around hyperscalers. There is the opportunity for us to understand those capabilities, but we want to invest in a way that we do not tie ourselves with any of the big hyperscalers because this is also a rapidly evolving market. At the moment, we are defining our framework principles from an agentic AI standpoint.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The ERP upgrade has a timetable attached to it. SAP maintains it will end mainstream support for ECC at the end of 2027, while extended support will be available until the end of 2030 at a two percent premium.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rizzotto is keen to see the migration as more than a technical project. &quot;We are not concerned about [the end of support] because we started a program two years ago,&quot; she said. &quot;This is a key overarching priority for us: the modernization of our landscape. But we want to make sure that these investments – which every company needs to do – generate value for the enterprise.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The modernization is part of it, but at the end of the day, what you want to do is to ensure that you provide your company with a strong foundation to be able to execute those processes better and at a lower cost. So the ERP timeline is there: we are planning to go live with North America and Latin America in H2 2026, and in September we are also kicking off the MEU and AMEA plans. But what is important is that you take this as an opportunity to get ready for the future.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Mondelēz plan also addresses the question of process standardization in large, diverse organizations. While creating a standard set of processes might look good on a whiteboard, the pain of getting to an ideal state can outweigh the benefits.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Rizzotto said: &quot;What we are looking for is not standardization for the sake of standardization, but we are looking to create the transparency that enables us to make the right choice on where we want to adopt, eventually adapt, or even assemble. A technology landscape can be modular, so you understand what capability you want to invest in terms of out-of-the-box. So [we are deciding whether to] adopt those capabilities or assemble capabilities that create a competitive advantage.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   With ERP projects as big as the one Mondelēz is taking on, the ultimate test is showing that getting thousands of employees to adopt new processes and investing millions of dollars in new technology can offer the business something to say it was all worth it. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> UK copper fired after faking keyboard taps using photo frame </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/uk_copper_struck_off_after/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:39:36 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Avon and Somerset Police this week confirmed a former officer was dismissed after she was found weighing her laptop keyboard down with photo frames to simulate activity.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The former officer, referred to only as Sergeant X, was dismissed following what police said was an accelerated hearing, which ultimately ruled she had committed gross misconduct.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sergeant X recorded keystrokes that were three to eight times the volume of her colleagues in similar roles.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Investigating the case, Avon and Somerset Police&#x27;s Professional Standards Department (PSD) concluded that Sergeant X deployed the trick during &quot;the majority of shifts&quot; she worked in April and May 2025.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The same woman&#x27;s keystrokes were recorded as abnormally high throughout 2024, the police said, and a formal investigation into her conduct began in June 2025.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to an official statement, Sergeant X &quot;admitted using a corner of a picture frame to weigh down the keys so her laptop would not go into sleep mode, and she could therefore monitor calls on a separate screen during a time in which she suffered challenges in her personal life.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The police did not describe the nature of these other calls, nor specify whether the woman was working from home at the time, although the latter sounds like a distinct possibility.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   contacted Avon and Somerset Police for further details.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Craig Holden, chair of the misconduct panel and former assistant chief constable, ruled that Sergeant X&#x27;s actions amounted to gross misconduct, but in a rare move, decided to preserve her anonymity &quot;after considering representations.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Detective superintendent Larisa Hunt, the head of the PSD, said: &quot;It is extremely disappointing an officer has behaved in a way which could not only discredit the police force, but also undermine the public confidence in respect of our duties and responsibilities.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We know officers and staff deal with immense pressure and high workloads, and while Sergeant X had some mitigating circumstances, it&#x27;s unacceptable for an officer to act in this deliberate and deceitful way by abusing the trust placed in her, by making it appear she was working when she was not.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We recognise the overwhelming majority of our officers and staff work hard to protect the public.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   According to ExpressVPN research in 2025, 85 percent of British workplaces
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/30/forget_the_idea_of_wfh/&quot;&gt;
    snoop on remote staff&#x27;s activity
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Of all the employers to track this kind of thing, we would imagine that the police would be high among the organizations with the most oversight.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/gchq_ciso_job/&quot;&gt;
     GCHQ dangles up to £130K for a CISO to fight the world&#x27;s most capable adversaries
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/26/copilot_courts_system/&quot;&gt;
     Britain&#x27;s creaking courts to use Copilot for transcriptions
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/23/cma_amazon_exec/&quot;&gt;
     Ex-Amazon UK boss lined up to chair Britain&#x27;s competition watchdog
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/19/uk_intimate_images_online/&quot;&gt;
     UK to demand social platforms take down abusive intimate images within 48 hours
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   WFH-ers looking for more sophisticated ways of deceiving productivity-tracking employers could look for the classic mouse jigglers, which come in hardware and software forms and are available for as cheap as just a few dollars.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   There is also no shortage of options for automatic keyboard presser machines, either to buy or 3D print, should you have the means.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Don&#x27;t confuse this with an official
   &lt;em&gt;
    Reg
   &lt;/em&gt;
   endorsement for such practices, however. You never know how sophisticated any employer&#x27;s methods of tracking remote workers are. Some won&#x27;t even detect activity on second monitors, while others, like Avon and Somerset Police&#x27;s, will compare your keystroke volume to your peers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Sergeant X&#x27;s case is not an isolated one. US bank
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/06/13/wells_fargo_fires_employees/&quot;&gt;
    Wells Fargo ousted at least a dozen staffers
   &lt;/a&gt;
   from its wealth management and investment management divisions in 2024 for falsifying keyboard activity. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> AI agents need orchestration - not just intelligence </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/ai_agents_need_orchestration/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:07:26 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Most organizations chasing enterprise automation have already solved the easy part. They&#x27;ve built AI agents, deployed digital workers, connected a handful of systems. What they haven&#x27;t cracked is how to get all of those pieces to work together without somebody&#x27;s compliance team losing sleep. The coordination problem, not the intelligence problem, is where most agentic ambitions quietly stall.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   On
   &lt;strong&gt;
    April 28, 2026
   &lt;/strong&gt;
   , SS&amp;C Blue Prism plans to address that gap head-on with the global virtual launch of WorkHQ. It&#x27;s a unified agentic automation platform designed to let enterprises design, orchestrate, and govern work across people, AI agents, digital workers, APIs, and existing systems — all from a single environment.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The live broadcast runs from
   &lt;strong&gt;
    9:30am to 11:00am EST
   &lt;/strong&gt;
   , and the pitch is straightforward: agentic operations that work in practice, with governance, real use cases, and strategic insight. Expect SS&amp;C Blue Prism to show rather than merely tell. Attendees will see live demonstrations of WorkHQ coordinating workflows across AI agents, digital workers, applications and the legacy systems many enterprises can&#x27;t afford to rip out.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Strategic perspectives from AWS and IDC will complement  customer stories. Attendees will come away with a sharper picture of how orchestration, governance, and automation  intersect, and  the business impact of WorkHQ  well beyond the proof of concept.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Governance deserves particular attention. AI agents are proliferating across enterprises far faster than the frameworks meant to keep them accountable, and the resulting gap is a genuine operational risk. During the launch event, attendees will learn about WorkHQ&#x27;s emphasis on control. Its agents not only interpret context and make decisions, but they do so within defined security, compliance, and governance guardrails. Low-code tooling means business users (not just developers) can build and manage those governed workflows. And SS&amp;C Blue Prism’s enterprise operating model provides the framework for deploying AI into business operations responsibly, at scale, and with maximum impact.
   &lt;span&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The proposition is that the missing layer isn&#x27;t more intelligence; it&#x27;s the connective tissue that lets humans, agents, and systems collaborate securely and at scale.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The event runs from
   &lt;strong&gt;
    9:30-11:00am EST on April 28, 2026
   &lt;/strong&gt;
   . It is a live global broadcast, free to attend virtually from anywhere. If orchestrating agentic operations is on your radar,
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssc.registration.goldcast.io/webinar/222edb4e-2e8a-467d-8740-c392053584b9?utm_campaign=gl-brand-2026-q1-01-30-bp-live-virtual-&amp;utm_source=theregister&amp;utm_medium=cs&amp;utm_content=digital-event&quot;&gt;
    register here
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Engineer held hostage by client who asked for the wrong fix </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/on_call/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:32:16 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Friday has arrived, bringing a promise of fleeting freedom – and a new instalment of On Call,
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   &#x27;s reader-contributed column that retells your tales of tech support incidents that became memorable for all the wrong reasons.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This week, meet a reader we&#x27;ll Regomize as &quot;Kent&quot; who told us he once worked as a field engineer and shares a story of the time a client dispatched him to a private datacenter to replace a failed system board in an HP server.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;A straightforward job,&quot; Kent told On Call. &quot;Board swap, set serial number and BIOS options, bring it through POST, confirm hardware health, hand it back. Flee.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Kent arrived at the datacenter and made it through what he called &quot;the usual mantrap routine&quot; – the combination of revolving doors and swipe-card barriers that properly secure datacenters use to regulate entries and exits.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Once inside he found the server, tested to verify the system board had failed – and saw it had. He therefore replaced it, reseated the RAM and CPU, put everything back together and turned the machine on.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   It booted, everything worked as intended, and the client&#x27;s admin logged in and verified all was well – and then started talking to someone else about what sounded like a software upgrade.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Kent didn&#x27;t stick around to learn more.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;My brief was to swap a board. The board was swapped,&quot; he told On Call. So he packed up the failed board and his tools, then left.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   On his way out, Kent swiped his card and the mantrap gate didn&#x27;t open. A short time later he tried again, without success.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;After a few minutes I called out to the security desk behind the glass and the guard checked his screen and said: ‘We&#x27;ve been told to hold you. The admin says there&#x27;s still a problem with the server.&#x27;&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   This was a surprise to Kent, who just a few minutes earlier had watched the server boot and heard the client&#x27;s admin acknowledge the fact.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fifteen minutes later nobody had explained what was going on.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Kent called his dispatcher, who called the client. &quot;The message relayed back was that they were &#x27;still having issues,&#x27; and I was not to be released until they were resolved.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;At this point I was no longer a field engineer. I was collateral,&quot; Kent told On Call.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/20/on_call/&quot;&gt;
     Desktop tech sent to prison for an education on strange places to put tattoos
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/13/on_call/&quot;&gt;
     Enforcing piracy policy earned helpdesk worker death threats
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/06/on_call/&quot;&gt;
     New hire fixed a problem so fast, their boss left to become a yoga instructor
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/30/on_call/&quot;&gt;
     In-house techies fixed faults before outsourced help even noticed they&#x27;d happened
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   One hour and forty-five minutes later, Kent&#x27;s supervisor called for a three-way chat with the client.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The tone had shifted,&quot; Kent wrote. &quot;My supervisor calmly informed them that if I was not released immediately, I had two options available to me: pull the fire alarm inside the datacenter or call Police.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The client decided to let Kent leave.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   He later learned why he&#x27;d been detained.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;An application running on the server was malfunctioning,&quot; he told On Call. &quot;The application vendor blamed the operating system. The operating system vendor suggested the hardware might be unstable. The hardware had just had a board replaced. Therefore, the man who replaced the board must be the problem.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   20 minutes after Kent left the datacenter, his phone rang.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;The client&#x27;s admin called my mobile – not to apologize, but to inform me that I was banned from the site.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Kent thinks his crime was to successfully replace a motherboard in a server that ran a buggy application.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;My brief was to swap a board,&quot; he told On Call. &quot;The board was swapped.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Has a client or a colleague ever kept you on site against your will? If so, release your story by
   &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:oncall@theregister.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    clicking here
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to send On Call an email so we can share your story on a future Friday. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> Google catches Beijing spies using Sheets to spread espionage across 4 continents </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/25/google_and_friends_disrupt_unc2814/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:14:07 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   A China-linked crew found a unique formula for attacking telcos and government orgs across the Americas, Asia, and Africa in its latest round of intrusions. Google&#x27;s threat intelligence, along with unnamed industry partners, disrupted the gang, which used the Chocolate Factory&#x27;s own spreadsheet tools as part of its exploits.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Chocolate Factory announced the Google Threat Intelligence Group-led actions on Wednesday and said that, in partnership with other teams, it terminated all Google Cloud Projects that had been controlled by UNC2814, a group that GTIG has tracked since 2017. They also disabled all known UNC2814 infrastructure and accounts, and revoked access to the Google Sheets API calls used by the Chinese snoops for command-and-control (C2) purposes.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;As of Feb. 18, GTIG&#x27;s investigation confirmed that UNC2814 has impacted 53 victims in 42 countries across four continents, and identified suspected infections in at least 20 more countries,&quot; the threat hunters
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/disrupting-gridtide-global-espionage-campaign&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    said
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in the report.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   They also noted that UNC2814 has no observed overlap with
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/08/salt_typhoon_domains/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    Salt Typhoon
   &lt;/a&gt;
   , another Beijing-backed group that
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/06/charter_consolidated_windstream_salt_typhoon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    hacked America&#x27;s major telecommunications firms
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/12/09/white_house_salt_typhoon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    stole information
   &lt;/a&gt;
   belonging to
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/fbi_cyber_cop_salt_typhoon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    nearly every American
   &lt;/a&gt;
   beginning as far back as 2019.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Googlers don&#x27;t know how UNC2814 gained initial access to victims&#x27; environments for this particular campaign, but said the suspected Chinese government goon squad historically breaks in by exploiting and compromising web servers and edge systems.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;We don&#x27;t have visibility into the specific targeting, but previous PRC-nexus espionage intrusions against telecoms have targeted individuals and organizations for surveillance efforts, particularly dissidents and activists, as well as traditional espionage targets,&quot; GTIG tech lead Dan Perez told
   &lt;em&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/em&gt;
   . &quot;The kind of access UNC2814 achieved during this campaign would likely enable this kind of operation.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Perez declined to name the specific industry partners that GTIG worked with to take down the threat group&#x27;s infrastructure.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The security sleuths uncovered this campaign during a Mandiant investigation into suspicious activity in a customer&#x27;s environment. Specifically, this binary, &quot;/var/tmp/xapt,&quot; initiated a shell with root privileges, and then executed a command to retrieve the system’s user and group identifiers to confirm it had successfully escalated to root.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Google suspects the payload was named xapt, after the command-line tool in Debian and Ubuntu systems, to make it easier to hide in the victim&#x27;s environment and look like a legitimate tool.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/12/google_china_apt31_gemini/&quot;&gt;
     Google: China&#x27;s APT31 used Gemini to plan cyberattacks against US orgs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/10/singapore_telco_espionage/&quot;&gt;
     Singapore spent 11 months booting China-linked snoops out of telco networks
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/17/volt_typhoon_dragos/&quot;&gt;
     China remains embedded in US energy networks &#x27;for the purpose of taking it down&#x27;
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/24/fcc_salt_typhoon_rules/&quot;&gt;
     FCC guts post-Salt Typhoon telco rules despite ongoing espionage risk
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The intruders also used a novel backdoor, Gridtide, that abuses legitimate Google Sheets API functionality to disguise its command-and-control (C2) traffic. Mandiant has linked Gridtide to UNC2814.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   After breaking in, the spies moved laterally via SSH, performed reconnaissance, escalated privileges, and then deployed the Gridtide backdoor using a command, &quot;nohup ./xapt,&quot; that allows it to run even after the user closes the session.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &quot;Subsequently, SoftEther VPN Bridge was deployed to establish an outbound encrypted connection to an external IP address,&quot; the threat intel team wrote. &quot;VPN configuration metadata suggests UNC2814 has been leveraging this specific infrastructure since July 2018.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The C-based backdoor uses Google Sheets as its C2 platform, can execute shell commands, and can upload and download files. In this case, the attacker deployed Gridtide on an endpoint containing personal information - likely to identify and track persons of interest - including full name, phone number, date and place of birth, voter ID and national ID numbers.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   While Google&#x27;s responders didn&#x27;t observe any actual data theft, previous Chinese government espionage campaigns have involved
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2026/01/27/chinalinked_hackers_accused_of_yearslong/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    stealing call data records
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and unencrypted SMS messages, and abusing
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/04/encryption_backdoor_debate/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    telecoms&#x27; legal wiretapping systems
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   GTIG says it has notified all victims of this campaign, and is &quot;actively supporting&quot; those who have been compromised. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> NUC, NUC! Who’s there? ASUS with a thin client for Microsoft’s cloudy PCs </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/microsoft_dell_asus_windows_365/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:58:39 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Microsoft has found some friends to make desktop devices that boot into its Windows 365 cloud PCs.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The software giant was previously the only vendor to make such machines, in the form of the Windows 365 Link machines it
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/11/19/microsoft_windows_365_link/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    debuted
   &lt;/a&gt;
   in 2024 and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/04/03/windows_365_link/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    delivered
   &lt;/a&gt;
   the next year.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Dell and ASUS have now joined the cloudy PC party.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   ASUS’s model is the NUC 16 for Windows 365. Readers may recall that “NUC” stands for Next Unit of Computing, a brand Intel coined for a range of PCs it and later
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/07/19/intel_asus_nuc_deal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    sold
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to ASUS.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   After the Taiwanese company acquired NUCs, ASUS told
   &lt;i&gt;
    The Register
   &lt;/i&gt;
   it
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/08/asus_nuc_year_one/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    wanted
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to take the machines into new markets.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   And now it has, and
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.connect.asus.com/notify-me-ASUS-NUC-16-Windows-365&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    says
   &lt;/a&gt;
   its machine offers “the latest Intel processor” without specifying a model, but promises DDR5 memory, Wi-Fi 6E, 2.5GbE LAN, Bluetooth 5.3, HDMI, USB Type-C, and USB Type-A ports will all be present in the 0.7-liter device and that it can support three displays.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Dell’s device is the Pro Desktop for Windows 365. The company hasn&#x27;t offered any specs beyond a promise it can drive three displays.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Microsoft says tweaks to the minimalist “Cloud CPC” OS that runs on the machines will add support for pairing Bluetooth devices “during the out-of-box experience” and support for custom branding on the sign-in screen.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The software giant suggests these devices as especially secure and manageable, because they don’t require users to store anything on the device or on-premises – apps and data are all in Azure. Of course the company says its own Intune tool makes conventional PCs easy to secure and manage, too. And to complicate matters further, Microsoft also offers tech that allows
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/05/24/windows_365_boot_preview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    vanilla PCs
   &lt;/a&gt;
   to boot straight into a cloudy PC instead of starting up a local version of Windows, or
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/18/microsoft_cloud_apps_omnissa_update/?_gl=1*1lb1dmn*_ga*MTI0MjE1MDMxNS4xNzE5OTg5NTg5*_ga_JXW44Y23NM*czE3NzIxNTc2ODkkbzE5MzQkZzEkdDE3NzIxNzA0MTckajQxJGwwJGgw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    streaming apps that don’t need a PC at all
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/19/microsoft_virtual_pc_update/&quot;&gt;
     Microsoft reveals new cloudy AI PC that’s not a Copilot+ PC
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/06/24/omnissa_appvolumes_physical_extension/&quot;&gt;
     Omnissa brings VDI-style app packaging to physical PCs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/05/07/citrix_virtualisation_avoids_tariffs/&quot;&gt;
     Citrix finds new use for virtualization: Avoiding PC price hikes caused by tariffs
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/06/06/google_acquires_cameyo_vdi_challenge/&quot;&gt;
     Google takes on virtual desktops with acquisition of app-streamer Cameyo
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Microsoft cares about this stuff because around ten percent of PCs used by businesses are virtual. Analyst firm Gartner thinks that number will double by 2027 because cloudy virtual PCs accessed through a thin client can be
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/08/14/gartner_daas_predictions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    cheaper to run than laptops
   &lt;/a&gt;
   .
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Another factor that creates the possibility of winning more users for Windows 365 is Broadcom’s acquisition of VMware, which has seen the virtualization pioneer stop selling the kind of software bundles suited to running just desktop virtualization workloads. Some organizations therefore face a choice of signing up for VMware’s very capable but pricey Cloud Foundation private cloud bundle, or finding a new way to run virtual PCs.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Buyers must wait until Q3 for the debut of the new devices from ASUS and Dell. Microsoft, meanwhile, continues to sell its own Windows 365 Link devices. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
<item>
<title> China’s ‘The US hacks itself to make us look bad’ theorists return with a crypto conspiracy </title>
<link>https://www.theregister.com/2026/02/27/chinas_the_us_hacks_itself/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:24:30 -0000</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Chinese agency that has accused the USA of cyberattacks on its own infrastructure to make Beijing look bad is back with another theory: Washington’s actions against cryptocurrency crooks are just attempts to dominate the global financial system.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The agency behind these theories is China&#x27;s National Computer Virus Emergency Response Center (CVERC), which on Thursday published a document titled “Top Player: Analysis of Global Virtual Currency Assets Extortion under the U.S. Technological Hegemony.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The gist of it is that US actions such as
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2023/06/05/binance_us_sec_lawsuit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    prosecuting Binance co-founder Zhao Changpeng
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and chasing alleged cyber-scam camp operator Chen Zhi were not law enforcement actions but attempts to ensure US hegemony over cryptocurrencies and preserve the role of the US dollar as the de facto currency of world trade.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Even US president Donald Trump’s decision to pardon Zhao – which the commander in chief
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-pardon-of-crypto-billionaire-sparks-concerns-over-use-of-pardon-power-60-minutes-transcript/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    admitted
   &lt;/a&gt;
   he made without knowing anything about the case – was just a cunning ploy to ensure Binance complied with US law in future so Washington gains more power over global crypto markets.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   CVERC says the US also targeted crypto outfits to profit by collecting massive fines and auctioning stolen cryptocurrencies retrieved by American authorities. It also accuses Washington of using action against cryptocurrencies to build a strategic reserve of virtual currencies, a Trump administration policy.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The Chinese agency says Washington’s action against crypto companies is just one of its tactics, including “sponsored cyberattacks, weaponized technical standards, and digital cognitive warfare” that “serves its global expansion of political and economic interests while maintaining global hegemony.”
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/15/china_volt_typhoon_false_flag/&quot;&gt;
     China again claims Volt Typhoon cyber-attack crew was invented by the US to discredit it
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/12/cverc_prince_grou_scam_bitcoin/&quot;&gt;
     China hates crypto and scams, but is now outraged USA acquired bitcoin from a scammer
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/07/trump_signs_bitcoin_reserve_eo/&quot;&gt;
     Crypto takes a dip as Trump signs Bitcoin Reserve order
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/04/07/asia_tech_news_in_brief/&quot;&gt;
     Asian tech players react to US tariffs with delays, doubts, deal-making
    &lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   The document neglects to mention the inconvenient fact that China has extradited and arrested Chen Zhi – and issued death sentences for others associated with scam camps in Cambodia. Nor does it consider that the proceeds of crypto cases brought by the US Federal government represent a tiny fraction of the nation’s budget.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   CVERC’s screed ends by noting China’s stance on cryptocurrency – they’re dangerous and therefore illegal – and contrasting that with a suggestion the US could exercise extra-territorial jurisdiction to seize crypto anywhere, anytime.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Reality is, of course, rather more nuanced. The US has gone after suspected crypto-crooks outside its territory using well-established international procedures. However, the Trump administration has eased regulation on crypto companies, a contentious action as the Trump family has profited from its own virtual currency ventures. ®
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
